<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dewhurst Security Blog - Posts</title>
    <description>Information security blog for Dewhurst Security.</description>
    <link>
    https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Security Vulnerability in wpForo Forum WordPress Plugin</title>
        
          <description>Version 1.4.11, and below, of the wpForo Forum WordPress Plugin were found to be vulnerable to Reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). The vulnerability was due to the Plugin using the $_SERVER['REQUEST_URI'] PHP variable to create a URL string that was later output within HTML without any output encoding.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2018/06/01/wp-foro-wordpress-plugin-xss-vulnerability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2018/06/01/wp-foro-wordpress-plugin-xss-vulnerability.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Security Vulnerability in Loginizer WordPress Plugin</title>
        
          <description>Versions 1.3.8 to 1.3.9 of the Loginizer WordPress Plugin were found to be vulnerable to Stored Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). The vulnerability was due to the Plugin's logging functionality using the $_SERVER['REQUEST_URI'] PHP variable to create a URL string that was logged to the database without any input validation. The URL that was saved to the database was later output within HTML without any output encoding.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2018/05/22/loginizer-wordpress-plugin-xss-vulnerability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2018/05/22/loginizer-wordpress-plugin-xss-vulnerability.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Authenticated XSS Vulnerability in WP Statistics</title>
        
          <description>A few days ago the awesome folks over at Sucuri found a SQL Injection vulnerability in the popular WP Statistics WordPress Plugin, currently installed on over 300,000 websites. We wanted to check our  existing toolsets would have detected the vulnerability so that we could ensure that Dewhurst Security clients were not affected by similar issues. During this process we identified the Authenticated Reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerability we discuss below. This vulnerability was responsibly disclosed to the vendor who patched the issue and released a new version in the same day.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/07/03/wp-statistics-authenticated-xss-vulnerability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/07/03/wp-statistics-authenticated-xss-vulnerability.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ExploitBox WordPress Security Advisories</title>
        
          <description>Yesterday, May 3rd 2017, a site named ExploitBox released two WordPress advisories discovered by Dawid Golunski. The titles of the two advisories are: WordPress Core &lt;= 4.7.4 Potential Unauthorized Password Reset (0day) and WordPress Core 4.6 - Unauthenticated Remote Code Execution (RCE) PoC Exploit (default configuration, no plugins, no auth).</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/05/04/exploitbox-wordpress-security-advisories.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/05/04/exploitbox-wordpress-security-advisories.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Installing WPScan on Windows 10</title>
        
          <description>We constantly get asked by users how to install WPScan on Windows machines. Since none of the core developers use Windows day to day, Windows is not officially supported by WPScan. Nevertheless, it is possible to install WPScan on Windows by using Bash on Windows. In this video we'll show you how to do just that, install WPScan on Windows 10.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/05/03/installing-wpscan-on-windows-10.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/05/03/installing-wpscan-on-windows-10.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WPScan Version 3.0 BETA Release</title>
        
          <description>Yesterday, January 28th 2017, members of the WPScan Team released WPScan version 3.0. WPScan is a black box WordPress Vulnerability Scanner written in Ruby which was released in 2011 for Penetration Testers. WPScan 3.0 is not just another release. It was re-written from the ground up by a WPScan team member, Erwan.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/01/28/wpscan-v3-release.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2017/01/28/wpscan-v3-release.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>YouTube Windows Exploit Suggester</title>
        
          <description>YouTube is fast becoming the number one choice for content on family TVs thanks to 'smart' TVs and gadgets like Google's Chromecast. Recording, editing and uploading videos is also becoming much easier. Almost everyone in the western world owns a powerful smart phone with a built in camera. Generally, people also have computers powerful enough to edit videos in less and less time. And finally, relatively fast Internet speeds to upload the final video (as well as consume videos).</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/11/22/youtube-windows-exploit-suggester.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/11/22/youtube-windows-exploit-suggester.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress Plugin Security Testing Cheat Sheet</title>
        
          <description>This cheat sheet was compiled by Dewhurst Security to record the knowledge gained when testing WordPress plugins for security issues for our clients. The security documentation provided by WordPress and found online for plugin security is sparse, outdated or unclear. This cheat sheet is intended for Penetration Testers who audit WordPress plugins or developers who wish to audit their own WordPress plugins.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/08/18/wordpress-plugin-security-cheat-sheet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/08/18/wordpress-plugin-security-cheat-sheet.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OSVDB Shut Down</title>
        
          <description>On April 5th the Open Sourced Vulnerability Database (OSVDB) announced that they were shutting down. 

 For me, the writing was on the wall when OSVDB implemented CloudFlare's DDoS protection which makes you wait 5 seconds on a loading screen before you are able to access the site. It was not so much the waiting that alluded to the potential ending of OSVDB, it was that OSVDB's Google PageRank was taking a battering. So much that searching for terms such as 'OSVDB $somid' would not result in a osvdb.org hit on Google's front page.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/04/07/osvdb-shut-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/04/07/osvdb-shut-down.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Google Chrome Protocol Handler Fun</title>
        
          <description>You're probably all familiar of the custom protocol handlers browsers use for various things such as ```chrome://settings/``` and ```chrome://credits/```. I was using a Chrome app (extension) the other day that suggested I copy and pasted ```chrome://restart``` in to my browser address bar to restart Chrome. This got me thinking about the ```chrome``` protocol handler, what other ones are there and how they might they be able to be used for a bit of fun. 

 The first obvious bit of fun we could have is if someone clicked on a HTML link to ```chrome://restart``` and have their browser restart, losing all of their open tabs. This is so obvious that Chrome do not allow this to happen by default and you will see the following error in the browser console ```Not allowed to load local resource: chrome://restart/```.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/04/07/google-chrome-protocol-handler-fun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2016/04/07/google-chrome-protocol-handler-fun.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Mobile Security Certificate Pinning</title>
        
          <description>Certificate Pinning is an extra layer of security that is used by applications to ensure that the certificate provided by the remote server is the one which is expected. 

 By including the remote server’s x509 certificate or public key within the application, it is possible to compare the locally stored certificate or key with the one provided by the remote server. 

 If you have been unable to intercept (Man-in-the-Middle) the application’s HTTPS traffic, after taking the necessary steps, this is probably due to the application using Certificate Pinning.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/11/10/mobile-security-certificate-pining.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/11/10/mobile-security-certificate-pining.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Application Security Verification Standard (ASVS)</title>
        
          <description>A few days ago (October, 2015) the OWASP Application Security Verification Standard (ASVS) version 3.0 was released which I had the opportunity to contribute to in a small way by helping review some of the draft documents before the official release. 

 I became aware of the OWASP ASVS as a growing number of my clients started asking if I used it. At the time I didn't use it but I decided to invest some time into finding out what it was. This blog post's intention is to bring some attention to the OWASP ASVS project for those unaware of it.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/10/11/owasp-asvs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/10/11/owasp-asvs.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Scanner Outbound Calls</title>
        
          <description>Today Burp Suite announced the release of a new feature they call Burp Collaborator which is enabled by default. 

 By default this new feature makes use of a third-party server hosted by Burp to detect vulnerabilities which are not easily detectable in the usual 'request&lt;-&gt;response' method most vulnerability scanners use. 

 The legitimate concern of some people online has been that client information may now be leaked to Burp or worse leaked to the Internet if the third-party server Burp uses is ever compromised. </description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/04/17/scanner-outbound-calls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/04/17/scanner-outbound-calls.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WPScan Licensing</title>
        
          <description>When you first release software online you don't put too much thought into the software license (I didn't at least). You have no idea if the project will take off. If your intention is for your peers to use it freely your first thought may be Open Source. The most popular Open Source license is the GNU GPL, so why not use that!? 

 I released WPScan on the 16th of June 2011 along with the GNU GPL license. After a while I built up a team, The WPScan Team, which were people who had the same goals as me, to make an awesome black box WordPress scanning tool. The WPScan Team (3 other awesome people) and I have been working on WPScan in our spare time as volunteers for almost 4 years. Countless hours, days, weeks and months of man hours have been put into WPScan and recently the WPScan Vulnerability Database by us.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/01/21/wpscan-licensing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2015/01/21/wpscan-licensing.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2014 Achievements</title>
        
          <description>It's almost the end of the year so I thought I would take the opportunity to reflect on my achievements during 2014 before the holidays start. It is a good way for me to put the year into perspective and focus on my goals for 2015.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/12/12/2014-achievements.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/12/12/2014-achievements.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How I hacked Facebook</title>
        
          <description>Ok, ok. I didn't quite 'hack Facebook'. What I did was execute OS level commands on one of Facebook's acquisition's servers. This is how I did it.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/12/09/how-i-hacked-facebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/12/09/how-i-hacked-facebook.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WPScan Installation &amp; Introduction</title>
        
          <description>At WPScan we sometimes get users who strugle installing and using WPScan. I have made a video which shows the installation steps and an introduction to using WPScan for these users.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/11/20/wpscan-installation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/11/20/wpscan-installation.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Memcached</title>
        
          <description>Last week I came across a service on the Internet running on TCP port 11211, Memcached's default port. I had heard of Memcached before but I probably only knew it was some kind of database system, that was the extent of my familiarity with it. 

 I quickly learnt that connecting to Memcached does not require authentication. Authentication can be implmented but even then Memcached's own documentation says it should not be fully trusted.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/10/12/memcached.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/10/12/memcached.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WPScan and WordPress Security Interview</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was asked to do an interview about WPScan and WordPress security in general. Thought I'd share it here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/k0aZGK8sbJI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 13:59:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/07/10/wpscan-and-wordpress-security-interview.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/07/10/wpscan-and-wordpress-security-interview.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BruCON 5by5 - WPScan Online Vulnerability Database</title>
        
          <description>For those of you who have been living under a rock, &lt;a href=&quot;http://2014.brucon.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;BruCON&lt;/a&gt; is a security conference held every year in Belgium (originally Brussels, now Ghent). I have attended every BruCON conference since the second. Last year was the 5th time the conference had been held (correct me if I'm wrong) and so the year before (2012) they setup what they called &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.brucon.org/2012/10/announcing-brucon-5by5.html&quot;&gt;5by5&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed BruCON, as it's a non-for-profit, to share its extra left over cash by supporting community projects.

Last year, they allocated &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.brucon.org/2013/02/the-5by5-race-is-on.html&quot;&gt;up to 5,000 euros to 4 different community projects&lt;/a&gt;. These projects were:

1. OWASP OWTF (Abraham Aranguren)
2. The Cloudbug Project (Carlos Garcia Prado)
3. A tool a month (Robin Wood)
4. Eccentric Authentication (Guido Witmond)

As last year was such a success, they're doing it again this year! And this year I put in a proposal!

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 21:21:43 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/02/11/brucon-5by5-wpscan-online-vulnerability-database.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2014/02/11/brucon-5by5-wpscan-online-vulnerability-database.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>What passwords is GitHub banning?</title>
        
          <description>GitHub was recently the target of a large weak password brute force attack which involved &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/1698-weak-passwords-brute-forced&quot;&gt;40k unique IP addresses&lt;/a&gt;. One of many of the security measures GitHub has now taken is to ban users to register with 'commonly-used weak passwords'.

To find out what GitHub considers as 'commonly-used weak passwords' I decided to compile a list of GitHub valid passwords from a few password lists found online and one of my own.

GitHub's password policy is reasonable (at least 7 chars, 1 number and 1 letter) so from all of the wordlists used only 331 passwords were found to conform to GitHub's password policy.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 19:23:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/11/20/what-passwords-is-github-banning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/11/20/what-passwords-is-github-banning.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>SimpleRisk v.20130915-01 CSRF-XSS Account Compromise</title>
        
          <description>1. *Advisory Information*

Title: SimpleRisk v.20130915-01 CSRF-XSS Account Compromise
Advisory ID: RS-2013-0001
Date Published: 2013-09-30

2. *Vulnerability Information*

Type: Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) [CWE-352, OWASP-A8], Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) [CWE-79, OWASP-A3]
Impact: Full Account Compromise
Remotely Exploitable: Yes
Locally Exploitable: Yes
Severity: High
CVE-ID: CVE-2013-5748 (CSRF) and CVE-2013-5749 (non-httponly cookie)

3. *Software Description*

SimpleRisk a simple and free tool to perform risk management activities. Based entirely on open source technologies and sporting a Mozilla Public License 2.0, a SimpleRisk instance can be stood up in minutes and instantly provides the security professional with the ability to submit risks, plan mitigations, facilitate management reviews, prioritize for project planning, and track regular reviews. It is highly configurable and includes dynamic reporting and the ability to tweak risk formulas on the fly. It is under active development with new features being added all the time. SimpleRisk is truly Enterprise Risk Management simplified. [0]

Homepage: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simplerisk.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.simplerisk.org/&lt;/a&gt;
Download: &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplerisk.googlecode.com/files/simplerisk-20130915-001.tgz&quot;&gt;https://simplerisk.googlecode.com/files/simplerisk-20130915-001.tgz&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 23:15:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/09/30/simplerisk-v-20130915-01-csrf-xss-account-compromise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/09/30/simplerisk-v-20130915-01-csrf-xss-account-compromise.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Security Testing HTML5 WebSockets</title>
        
          <description>Recently I became faced with my first Web Application Security Assessment which relied heavily on HTML5's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/websockets/basics/&quot;&gt;WebSockets&lt;/a&gt;.

The first clue that the application was using WebSockets was when the application kept giving me a timeout error while using my proxy of choice, &lt;a href=&quot;http://portswigger.net/burp/&quot;&gt;Burp Suite&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at the HTTP requests/responses in Burp I noticed that a large JavaScript file was requested and downloaded from the server. Within this file I noticed a URL with the &lt;em&gt;ws://&lt;/em&gt; scheme, the WebSocket scheme.

&lt;h3&gt;TCP/HTTP?&lt;/h3&gt;

The initial WebSocket handshake is carried out over HTTP using an '&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP/1.1_Upgrade_header&quot;&gt;upgrade request&lt;/a&gt;'. After the initial exchange over HTTP all future communication is carried out over TCP. On the application I was testing the WebSocket handshake over HTTP within &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;WireShark&lt;/a&gt; looked like this:

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 19:57:45 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/30/security-testing-html5-websockets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/30/security-testing-html5-websockets.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Zone Transfers on The Alexa Top 1 Million Part 2</title>
        
          <description>In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/zone-transfers-on-the-alexa-top-1-million/&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this blog post I conducted a DNS Zone Transfer (axfr) against the top 2000 sites of the Alexa Top 1 Million. I did this to create a better subdomain brute forcing word list. At the time, conducting the Zone Transfer against the top 2000 sites took about 12 hours, this was using a single threaded bash script. I was pretty proud of this achievement at the time and thought that doing the same for the whole top 1 million sites was beyond the time and resources that I had.

After creating a multithreaded and parallelised PoC in Ruby to do the Zone Transfers, it took about 5 minutes to conduct the Zone Transfers against the top 2000 compared to the 12 hours it took me to do the top 2000 using a single thread. I decided it was possible to do a Zone Transfer against the whole top 1 million sites.

There were 60,472 successful Zone Transfers (%6) out of the Alexa Top 1 Million, this equates to 566MB of raw data on disk. This amount of data brings its own challenges when attempting to manipulate it.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 23:06:36 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/08/zone-transfers-on-the-alexa-top-1-million-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/08/zone-transfers-on-the-alexa-top-1-million-part-2.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Zone Transfers on The Alexa Top 1 Million</title>
        
          <description>At work as part of every assessment we do a some reconnaissance which includes attempting a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_zone_transfer&quot;&gt;DNS Zone Transfer (axfr)&lt;/a&gt; and conducting a subdomain brute force on the target domain/s. The subdomain brute force is only as good as your wordlist, the Zone Transfer is a matter of luck.

Alexa release a list of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/alexa-static/top-1m.csv.zip&quot;&gt;top 1 million sites&lt;/a&gt; which is updated on a daily basis. To create a better subdomain wordlist to conduct subdomain brute forcing I attempted a DNS Zone Transfer against the first 2000 sites in the Alexa Top 1 Million list. With every successful Zone Transfer the DNS A records were stored in a CSV file.

This was all done using Carlos Perez's &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/darkoperator/dnsrecon&quot;&gt;dnsrecon&lt;/a&gt; DNS enumeration tool. Dnsrecon was ever so slightly modified to only save A records, apart from that I just used a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/ethicalhack3r/6145925&quot;&gt;bash script&lt;/a&gt; to iterate over the Top 1 Million list and ran dnsrecon's axfr option for each site with CSV output enabled.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 13:37:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/03/zone-transfers-on-the-alexa-top-1-million.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/08/03/zone-transfers-on-the-alexa-top-1-million.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cracking Microsoft Excel 97-2004 .xls Documents</title>
        
          <description>A client emailed to say they had forgotten a password for their Microsoft Excel .xls document and asked if it was possible to recover it. After searching on Google it was clear that there was plenty of shi...bloatware, which may have worked if you were willing to go through a few of them and pay a few dollars. It wasn't that important of a document according to the client but nevertheless a challenge is a challenge.

The document was encrypted when using 'save as', according to various sources online the encryption algorithm is 40bit RC4. As it is encrypted nothing could be gleaned by opening the document with a hex editor.

As always when Google turns up nothing useful I turn to Twitter. A few people recommended &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elcomsoft.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Elcomsoft&lt;/a&gt; which do Windows software to both recover and obtain the password of a Microsoft Excel document. This looked like a good bet and they offer free trials! The recover software which seems to do a brute force attack looked like it could have worked (especially now I know how weak the password was) but I was running the software on a Virtual Machine. The recovery tool unfortunately didn't reveal the password, the paid for version may have, I don't know.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 17:58:57 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/07/26/cracking-microsoft-excel-97-2004-xls-documents.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/07/26/cracking-microsoft-excel-97-2004-xls-documents.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Login Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)</title>
        
          <description>The new OWASP Top 10 2013 was released not so long ago, while reading over it I noticed this:

&quot;Attackers can trick victims into performing any state changing operation the victim is authorized to perform, e.g., updating account details, making purchases, logout and &lt;strong&gt;even login&lt;/strong&gt;.&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-A8-Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-A8-Cross-Site_Request_Forgery_(CSRF)&lt;/a&gt;

This must be a mistake I thought, why would you ever want to CSRF a user to log them into their own account? If you already had their login credentials this must be utterly pointless.

Today I came across an academic paper which gives three examples of why Login CSRF can be an issue and how wrong I was.

&lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt;

&quot;Search History. Many search engines, including Yahoo! and Google, allow their users to opt-in to saving their search history and provide an interface for a user to review his or her personal search history. Search queries contain sensitive details about the user’s interests and activities [41, 4] and could be used by an attacker to embarrass the user, to steal the user’s identity, or to spy on the user. An attacker can spy on a user’s search history by logging the user into the search engine as the attacker; see Figure 1. The user’s search queries are then stored in the attacker’s search history, and the attacker can retrieve the queries by logging into his or her own account.&quot;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 22:01:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/06/20/login-cross-site-request-forgery-csrf.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/06/20/login-cross-site-request-forgery-csrf.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>HTTP Form Password Brute Forcing - The Need for Speed</title>
        
          <description>HTTP Form password brute forcing is not rocket science, you try multiple username/password combinations until you get a correct answer (or non-negative answer).

Password brute forcing, especially over a network, takes time and while your software is attempting to find a correct username/password combination it is taking up your and the remote system's resources. While the brute force is being carried out you might not want to run an automated scan, for example, as the remote server may not be able to cope with the amount of connections or the rapid succession of connections. At the same time, your network bandwidth and system memory are also limited. It makes sense that when you conduct a weak password brute force it is done as fast as possible so that your time and resources are restored for other tasks.

And of course not forgetting that you're always going to be limited by time on a pentest/web app assessment as the client's budget is never unlimited.

So what is the fastest way to brute force a HTTP form today? I use Burp Suite for my Web Application Security Assessments and I would normally use Burp's Intruder, but is this the fastest tool to do it with?

Of course, there are other limiting factors when brute forcing remotely such as your Internet/Network speed, CPU speed, RAM and the remote system's response times, as well as other factors. For this experiment we'll only be focusing on the software used to carry out the password brute force attack. This is far from being a perfect in-depth study but it should hopefully give an idea which tool out of my small collection (Burp Intruder Spider Vs Hydra http-post-form) is fastest.

&lt;strong&gt;The Setup&lt;/strong&gt;

On both tools I set one user to brute force, admin, and used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethicalhack3r.co.uk/files/fuzzing/rockyou-75.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rockyou-75.txt&lt;/a&gt; wordlist (19963 lines), which has one addition which is the correct password which was added to the last line of the file. Both the same username and password list was used for Burp's Intruder (Sniper) and Hydra. Each tool was run one after the other, not at the same time.

Burp Suite Professional Intruder (Sniper) Version: 1.5.11
Hydra (http-post-form) Version: 7.4.2

A &quot;Local&quot; test was carried out on a localhost Apache 2 web server as well as a &quot;Remote&quot; test against the www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk Nginx web server.

The &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/xV80ZHBj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Test Form&lt;/a&gt; that I created to test against (both locally and remotely) does not make a database call which is what would normally be expected on a real HTTP login form. I'd expect my test login form to reply quicker than if it had to make a database call. The 'Local' and 'Remote' columns represent the time it took the tool to find the correct password which was at the end of the wordlist.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 22:04:33 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/04/17/http-form-password-brute-forcing-the-need-for-speed.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/04/17/http-form-password-brute-forcing-the-need-for-speed.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>SSH &quot;accept : too many open files&quot; on OS X when using Burp</title>
        
          <description>&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 19.04.2013 10:17 ---&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;WARNING!&lt;/strong&gt; This did break the Tor Browser Bundle on my machine. The error was &quot;Couldn't set maximum number of file descriptors: Invalid argument&quot;
&lt;strong&gt;---&lt;/strong&gt;

For as long as I can remember, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://ocaoimh.ie/2008/02/13/how-to-use-ssh-as-a-proxy-server/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;using SSH as a forward proxy&lt;/a&gt; to proxy Burp Suite through an upstream server I have gotten a &quot;accept : too many open files&quot; error in my Mac OS X Terminal after a couple of hours of using Burp's Proxy and/or Scanner.

When searching Google the first solution I came across was to set the 'ulimit' to something higher, as far as I can tell 'ulimit' sets user system limits such as how many open files a user is allowed to have open at once.

On OS X when attempting to set this limit to 'unlimited' I always got an error, &quot;Neither the hard nor soft limit for &quot;maxfiles&quot; can be unlimited. Please use a numeric parameter for both.&quot;, or when setting the ulimit to something higher than the default (256) the error (accept : too many open files) would still not go away or at least not for long. The only thing I found that would get rid of the error was to kill my ssh session and spawn a new one.

After further reading, some forums and blogs suggested updating openssh, I did this and the issue persisted. I thought the issue may have been openssl, so I updated that, the issue persisted.

I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ethicalhack3r/status/313982186695036928&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; about the issue where the suggestion of adjusting the ulimit resurfaced, but I just couldn't get ulimit to fix the issue.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 15:20:14 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/04/08/ssh-too-many-open-files-burp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/04/08/ssh-too-many-open-files-burp.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Weekly Viewing] You and Your Research &amp; Ruby 2.0</title>
        
          <description>This week we have another two videos lined up for you. The first, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haroonmeer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Haroon Meer&lt;/a&gt;, I was luckily enough to see in person at Brucon 2011. It is one of the best talks I have ever had the privilege to see, by anyone. If you're ever going to watch one of these 'Weekly Viewing' videos of mine make it be this one.

The second video is by Matz, the creator of Ruby, where he talks about Ruby's development and the new features of Ruby 2.0. In his talk Matz says that Ruby 1.8 will die soon. So update already! ;)

&lt;h1&gt;#HITB2012KUL D1T2 - Haroon Meer - You and Your Research&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JoVx_-bM8Tg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 11:50:55 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/16/weekly-viewing-you-and-your-research-ruby-2-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/16/weekly-viewing-you-and-your-research-ruby-2-0.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Weekly Viewing] Web App Security and Zero Days</title>
        
          <description>This is a first of hopefully many weekly posts in which I will share online security related videos that I've watched during the week and think are worth sharing. This week I've got two great videos lined up for your viewing pleasure.

&lt;h3&gt;[OWASP AppSec USA 2012] Effective Approaches to Web Application Security - Zane Lackey&lt;/h3&gt;

In this video Zane Lackey from Etsy talks about how to make a developer's job easier by making things safe by default, how to detect risky functionality and how to automate aspects of web application security monitoring and response.

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/54107692&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/54107692&quot;&gt;Effective Approaches to Web Application Security - Zane Lackey&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/appsecusa&quot;&gt;OWASP AppSec USA&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 12:00:14 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/10/weekly-viewing-web-app-security-and-zero-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/10/weekly-viewing-web-app-security-and-zero-days.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sony Freedom Of Information (FOI) Request</title>
        
          <description>On the 14th of January the UK Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) sent Sony Computer Entertainment Europe Limited a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ico.gov.uk/enforcement/~/media/documents/library/Data_Protection/Notices/sony_monetary_penalty_notice.ashx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;monetary penalty notice&lt;/a&gt; of £250,000 following 'a serious breach of the Data Protection Act'.

To be able to quantify how much the ICO was fining Sony for individual user's data the exact number of UK PSN users would need to be known. A couple of sources put this number at 3 million but I'm not sure where the original 3 million figure came from nor how accurate it really is [0][1].

If we were to take this 3 million figure at face value, the ICO fined Sony (£250,000 / 3,000,000) £0.000083 per user's data. According to the ICO, £250,000 is 'reasonable and proportionate' in this case. To get a more accurate figure I sent the ICO a FOI request to ask for the redacted figure in the monetary penalty notice document which simply states &quot;The Network Platform was used by an estimated REDACTED million customers in Europe, the Middle East, Africa, Australia and New Zealand with REDACTED million of those customers based in the UK.&quot;.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 19:30:23 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/07/sony-freedom-of-information-foi-request.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2013/03/07/sony-freedom-of-information-foi-request.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress plugin Asset manager upload.php Arbitrary Code Execution</title>
        
          <description>The '&lt;a href=&quot;http://1337day.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Inj3ct0r Team&lt;/a&gt;' compromised an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.exploithub.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ExploitHub.com&lt;/a&gt; database and released a &lt;a href=&quot;http://priv8.1337day.com/exploitHUB.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt; publicly which contained some of the data about the exploits that ExploitHub buy and sell.

I saw the file yesterday, had a quick skim over it, but didn't think too much of it. That is until WPScan team member &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/@gbrindisi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@gbrindisi&lt;/a&gt; pointed out that it contained 2 WordPress plugin vulnerabilities.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 20:10:38 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/12/wordpress-plugin-asset-manager-upload-php-arbitrary-code-execution.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/12/wordpress-plugin-asset-manager-upload-php-arbitrary-code-execution.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to the WordPress XML-RPC API</title>
        
          <description>WordPress 3.5 was recently released which now comes with the WordPress API &quot;always enabled&quot;. Personally I think this adds unnecessary risk by increasing the attack surface. How many WordPress user's actually use the API? I would put my money on it being a very small fraction, either way I'm sure the WordPress Core Development team had good reason to enable the API by default. After spending 5 minutes looking for where to turn the API off in WordPress 3.5 I gave up. Huh, I'll have another look sometime soon.

I've had a play with the API in the past, however, I've always found it hard to get going as the information on how to interact with the API is a bit sparse. Having played with it for an hour or so this evening I thought I'd share some of the information on how to get started (as well as a self reminder ;).

The latest API calls can be found on WordPress's Codex &lt;a href=&quot;http://codex.wordpress.org/XML-RPC_WordPress_API&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It doesn't list all available calls, to find these let's extract them from the 'wp-includes/class-wp-xmlrpc-server.php' file.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 20:27:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/11/introduction-to-the-wordpress-xml-rpc-api.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/11/introduction-to-the-wordpress-xml-rpc-api.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Female hackers at Abertay University</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Having completed a similar course at a different university, it is great to see that Abertay is attracting female students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/s5TFXGAfTH4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 14:53:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/06/female-hackers-at-abertay-university.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/12/06/female-hackers-at-abertay-university.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Implementing Basic Static Code Analysis into Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) to Reduce Software Vulnerabilities</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the paper that I submitted for my undergraduate dissertation in Ethical Hacking for Computer Security. The title (a mouth full) 'Implementing Basic Static Code Analysis into Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) to Reduce Software Vulnerabilities'. The paper talks about software security, modern software development, software development life cycles, static code analysis and a lot more. Since submitting it I have noticed some mistakes so I'm not putting this out there as a 'perfect paper'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper was the research and implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devbug.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DevBug&lt;/a&gt; an online PHP Static Code Analysis tool written mostly in JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to have a read through, I won't be making any future amendments as I was sick of looking at it by the time I submitted it but I thought I would put it out there incase it was useful to others in learning about software security. It is a bit dry in places, be warned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Implementing-Basic-Static-Code-Analysis-into-Integrated-Development-Environments-IDEs-to-Reduce-Software-Vulnerabilities.pdf&quot;&gt;Implementing Basic Static Code Analysis into Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) to Reduce Software Vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 14:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/09/21/implementing-basic-static-code-analysis-into-integrated-development-environments-ides-to-reduce-software-vulnerabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/09/21/implementing-basic-static-code-analysis-into-integrated-development-environments-ides-to-reduce-software-vulnerabilities.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Top 5 Blog Posts</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I've been running this blog now since November 2008. As the blog's 4 year anniversary is approaching I thought I would share with you the 5 blog posts which have received the most hits within that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/dropbox-security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DropBox Security&lt;/a&gt; - 20,494 hits&lt;br /&gt;
2. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/introducing-wpscan-wordpress-security-scanner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Introducing WPScan – WordPress Security Scanner&lt;/a&gt; - 13,012 hits&lt;br /&gt;
3. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/setting-up-tor-on-backtrack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Setting up Tor on BackTrack&lt;/a&gt; - 10,538 hits&lt;br /&gt;
4. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/wordpress-brute-force-tool/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress Brute Force Tool&lt;/a&gt; - 10,017 hits&lt;br /&gt;
5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/interview-the-jester/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;[Interview] The Jester&lt;/a&gt; - 7,475 hits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably not my personal top 5 blog posts but, nevertheless, the ones that get the most hits. If you would like to guest post on ethicalhack3r.co.uk in Spanish, English or French get in contact!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 14:42:24 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/09/15/top-5-blog-posts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/09/15/top-5-blog-posts.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Concrete5 5.5.2.1 Multiple Authenticated Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)</title>
        
          <description># Exploit Title: Concrete5 5.5.2.1 Multiple Authenticated Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)
# Date: 2012-08-25
# Author: Ryan 'ethicalhack3r' Dewhurst (www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk)
# Software Link: http://sourceforge.net/projects/concretecms/files/concrete5/5.5.2.1/
# Version: 5.5.2.1

1.Vulnerability Description

Multiple authenticated Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerabilities were identified within Concrete5 version 5.5.2.1. Also reported were some cookie security improvements. The first Concrete5 advisory can be found here [1].

2.Software Description

CMS made for Marketing but built for Geeks, concrete5 [0] is a content management system that is free and open source.

3. Vulnerability Information

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 11:05:16 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/08/25/concrete5-5-5-2-1-multiple-authenticated-cross-site-scripting-xss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/08/25/concrete5-5-5-2-1-multiple-authenticated-cross-site-scripting-xss.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sunday Ruby Coding: Caesar Cipher (ROT) Encoder/Decoder </title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a rainy Sunday so I wrote a Caesar Cipher (ROT) Encoder/Decoder in Ruby to ease the boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env ruby&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Caesar Cipher (ROT) Encoder/Decoder - Ryan 'ethicalhack3r' Dewhurst - 05.08.2012&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'a'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'z'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_a&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;gsub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/\s+/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;downcase&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encoded_forward&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;chr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher_position&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;plaintext&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encoded_forward&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_forward_count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_s&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Shifted &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; to '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;' - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encoded_forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;decode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;gsub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/\s+/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;downcase&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deciphered_forward&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;chr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clear_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clear_position&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cipher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deciphered_forward&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_forward_count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@alphabet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_s&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Shifted &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; to '&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;' - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deciphered_forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;position_forward_count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current_position&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_total&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current_position&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_difference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_total&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_total&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;position_total&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'[Decode]'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;decode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'W KHTXLFNEUZQ IRA MXPSVR  YHU WKH ODCB GRJ'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'[Encode]'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;encode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'plaintext'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 20:01:03 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/08/05/sunday-ruby-coding-caesar-cipher-rot-encoderdecoder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/08/05/sunday-ruby-coding-caesar-cipher-rot-encoderdecoder.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Freedom of Speech on Social Media</title>
        
          <description>There have been many cases recently where people in the UK have been arrested under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1988/27/contents&quot;&gt;Malicious Communications Act 1988&lt;/a&gt; as well as others such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2003/21/contents&quot;&gt;Communications Act of 2003&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2006/11/contents&quot;&gt;Terrorism Act 2006&lt;/a&gt; for what they have said on social media web sites such as Twitter or Facebook. Paul Chambers &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aolnews.com/2010/01/18/ill-advised-twitter-post-sparks-uk-terror-arrest/&quot;&gt;seems to have been the first&lt;/a&gt; in the UK to be arrested for what he said on Twitter in 2010. He later appealed and recently had his conviction &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2179782/Twitter-joke-trial-Paul-Chambers-wins-appeal-conviction-airport-bomb-Tweet.html&quot;&gt;quashed&lt;/a&gt;.

Some of these UK cases include:

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-19059127&quot;&gt;Tom Daley Twitter abuse: Police arrest boy in Weymouth&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webuser.co.uk/news/top-stories/438817/man-arrested-after-airport-bomb-joke-on-twitter&quot;&gt;Man arrested after airport bomb joke on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-14449673&quot;&gt;Twitter users in incitement arrest warning after riots&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/08/26/mensch_man_arrested/&quot;&gt;Cyber cops arrest man, 61, for menacing chick-lit MP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibtimes.co.uk/articles/196184/20110811/uk-riots-2011-police-arrest-three-individuals-for-attempting-to-incite-new-riot-london-manchester.htm&quot;&gt;UK Riots 2011: Police Arrest Three Individuals For Attempting to Incite New Riot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csmonitor.com/World/2011/0815/Flash-mobs-or-splash-mob-UK-man-arrested-for-planning-water-pistol-fight&quot;&gt;Flash mobs or splash mob? UK man arrested for planning water pistol fight.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/news/local-national/uk/tory-is-arrested-for-twitter-call-to-kill-columnist-15001967.html&quot;&gt;Tory is arrested for Twitter call to kill columnist&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itproportal.com/2011/08/10/scottish-teens-arrested-posting-facebook/&quot;&gt;Scottish teens arrested for posting on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 13:50:40 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/07/31/freedom-of-speech-on-social-media.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/07/31/freedom-of-speech-on-social-media.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>StaticBurp - Burp Suite potential DOM XSS Analysis</title>
        
          <description>A few weeks a go I had an idea.

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;JavaScript Taint Analysis for DOM &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%2523XSS&quot;&gt;#XSS&lt;/a&gt; in Burp would be an awesome feature to have! // cc: @&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/portswigger&quot;&gt;portswigger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ryan Dewhurst (@ethicalhack3r) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ethicalhack3r/status/218459472450961408&quot; data-datetime=&quot;2012-06-28T21:42:51+00:00&quot;&gt;June 28, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

When I get ideas that I think have something worth while in them I note them down for future reference.

The three main points to get this working were:

&lt;li&gt;Take Burp response body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extract JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform Taint Analysis.&lt;/li&gt;

The first step was to somehow extract HTML responses from Burp Suite, luckily someone had already written a Ruby Burp extender called &lt;a href=&quot;http://emonti.github.com/buby/&quot;&gt;Buby&lt;/a&gt;. I followed &lt;a href=&quot;http://carnal0wnage.attackresearch.com/2011/05/buby-script-basics-part-1.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; awesome series of blog posts to get myself aquatinted with Buby.

The next step is to extract the JavaScript from the HTML responses, this is quite trivial to do with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nokogiri.org/&quot;&gt;Nokogiri&lt;/a&gt; Ruby gem.

The third step is to analyse the extracted JavaScript for Sinks, Sources and Securing functions (Taint Analysis). This was the hard part, for me at least. Finding this information proved to be hard, I did find some data, however, in the end this is where I stopped pursuing my idea.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 14:38:39 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/07/19/staticburp-burp-suite-potential-dom-xss-analysis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/07/19/staticburp-burp-suite-potential-dom-xss-analysis.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DevBug - PHP Static Code Analysis</title>
        
          <description>My final year university dissertation was on the topic of Static Code Analysis, specifically the integration of IDEs (Integrated Development Environments) with Static Code Analysis. The idea was to make Static Code Analysis accesible to the developer, without them having to install and use additional specialist Static Code Analysis software.

Due to my familiarity with PHP and its lack of interpreter taint analysis I decided that I would write a PHP Static Code Analysis application. The PHP Static Code Analysis tool I developed is called DevBug, it is an online PHP Static Code Analysis tool written mostly in JavaScript (jQuery). The Static Code Analysis engine uses the sources, securing functions and sinks data from the awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/rips-scanner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RIPS&lt;/a&gt; Static Code Analysis tool to identify specific PHP functions that can cause or remediate user input caused vulnerabilities. DevBug uses Taint Analysis to identify tainted variables, follows the tainted variables through the code, untaints the variables if they are secured and finally detects whether or not tainted variables end up in in sensitive sinks.

The IDE used is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://codemirror.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CodeMirror&lt;/a&gt; that provides a code editing area, syntax highlighting, line numbering and an API. CodeMirror was slightly modified to detect deprecated PHP functions and highlight them.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 14:13:14 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/05/20/devbug-php-static-code-analysis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/05/20/devbug-php-static-code-analysis.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Old School hacking</title>
        
          <description>Back in the late nineties, around 1999, my mother bought me my first computer. Around this time The Matrix movie was released which as a young boy with a new computer had me Yahoo'ing (Google was largely unknown) for the term 'hacking'. Back then Yahoo! Chat was still around and had a chat room called the 'Hackers Lounge', everyone in there was talking about all sorts of cool things you could do with computers that I had never heard of before. With hindsight, most of the people in the chat room were script kiddies who knew how to run a few Windows GUI 'hacking' tools and largely acting like they were the kings of the Internet. At the time I wanted to learn about all of the cool things they knew. I started downloading and learning how to use these 'hacking' tools by the use of my guinea pig friends and family (my siblings soon grew tired of me remotely opening and closing their CD-ROM drives).

Some of these tools are still actively developed and used today, invaluable to conducting modern Penetration Testing and security audits. For the sake of nostalgia, I present to you some of the coolest most 1337 'hacking' tools that I and others used 'back in the day'. Warning: Download links not verified.

&lt;strong&gt;Legion by Rhino9&lt;/strong&gt;

Use: Windows Null Session share scanner.
Released: 1999
Platform: Windows
Further Info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=26263&amp;seqNum=5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=26263&amp;seqNum=5&lt;/a&gt;
Download: &lt;a href=&quot;http://packetstormsecurity.org/files/14711/legion.zip.html&quot; title=&quot;legion download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://packetstormsecurity.org/files/14711/legion.zip.html&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/legion_rhino9.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/legion_rhino9-300x229.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Legion Rhino9&quot; title=&quot;legion_rhino9&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;229&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-16768&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 21:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/05/09/old-school-hacking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/05/09/old-school-hacking.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Wireless Man In The Middle (MITM)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a recent piece I did for the BBC Inside Out program that originally aired on February 6th. In the video I demonstrate a wireless &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Main In The Middle (MITM)&lt;/a&gt; attack in a coffee shop using a FON+ wireless router, Karma and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digininja.org/jasager/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jasager&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, and they're the ones who call me an 'expert', personally, I hate the term and would never call myself one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/J6Lch5fhlO4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 19:41:47 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/02/13/wireless-man-in-the-middle-mitm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/02/13/wireless-man-in-the-middle-mitm.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Prevention of unwanted telemarketing calls</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am tired of receiving multiple telemarketing calls per day, I'm tired of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tpsonline.org.uk/tps/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Telephone Preference Service (TPS)&lt;/a&gt; not having an affect and I'm tired of telecommunication companies charging for prevention features which should be free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across an e-petition that was setup by a Rob Whitelock, it is not perfect in its recommendations but certainly puts the general point across.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;e-petitions is an easy way for you to influence government policy in the UK. You can create an e-petition about anything that the government is responsible for and if it gets at least 100,000 signatures, it will be eligible for debate in the House of Commons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can help by signing the petition here;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://epetitions.direct.gov.uk/petitions/17324&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://epetitions.direct.gov.uk/petitions/17324&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 15:54:12 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/01/20/prevention-of-unwanted-telemarketing-calls.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/01/20/prevention-of-unwanted-telemarketing-calls.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress 3.3 Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)</title>
        
          <description>Yesterday two Indian security researchers, Aditya Modha &amp; Samir Shah, released an &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldmanlab.blogspot.com/2012/01/wordpress-33-xss-vulnerability.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; outlining a Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerability within the latest version (at the time of writing) of WordPress 3.3. Many people started re-tweeting the news (including myself) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehackernews.com/2012/01/zero-day-reflected-cross-site-scripting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt; about it. The problem came when I tried to reproduce the vulnerability, I couldn't.

I started to think that the vulnerability was a miss-understanding or publicity stunt and was getting annoyed at the many people who were spreading miss-information. I contacted the researchers over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/oldmanlab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and told them that I was unable to reproduce the vulnerability in any browser or on any WordPress installation including vanilla installs.

The researchers got back in touch with a link to a WordPress installation on which the vulnerability worked. The URL they gave me was an IP address. Within their environment the XSS worked.

At this point I think even the researchers were puzzled. They sent me this code that they believed was the function causing the XSS within wp-includes/functions.php &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/iBnpN8Zm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://pastebin.com/iBnpN8Zm&lt;/a&gt;.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 19:56:14 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/01/03/wordpress-3-3-cross-site-scripting-xss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2012/01/03/wordpress-3-3-cross-site-scripting-xss.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress Plugin Disqus Comment System XSS</title>
        
          <description># Exploit Title: WordPress Plugin Disqus Comment System &lt; = 2.68 Reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)
# Google Dork: inurl:/wp-content/plugins/disqus-comment-system/
# Date: 11.12.11
# Author: Ryan Dewhurst (@ethicalhack3r)
# Software Link: http://downloads.wordpress.org/plugin/disqus-comment-system.2.68.zip
# Version: 2.68
# Tested on: Cross-Platform

** Vulnerability Description **

The WordPress Disqus Commment System version 2.68 was found to be effected by Reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). At the time of writing the plugin (not version) had been downloaded 504,746 times. [0]

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 17:15:17 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/12/11/wordpress-plugin-disqus-comment-system-xss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/12/11/wordpress-plugin-disqus-comment-system-xss.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>EC-Council - CEH - Unethical Behavior</title>
        
          <description>The EC-Council or 'The International Council of E-Commerce Consultants' as they like to call themselves offer a range of different services, mostly in the field of Information Security training and certifications. One of their certifications, the Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) claims to aspire to training 'ethical' hackers. 

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;CEHv7 provides a comprehensive ethical hacking and network security-training program to meet the standards of highly skilled security professionals.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

What I have found is the way the EC-Council promote their CEH is less than ethical and damn right unethical.

A comment left on my blog quite a while ago (2010/04/20 at 6:18 am), looked fairly authentic, however, when investigating a little further it was clear to me that the comment was in fact SPAM.

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;smith said...
Hey folks, Thanks for sharing your views,article includes a very good information about the ethical hacking, the most interesting job in the field of computer security is being an ethical hacker,so i striven into the field of CEH, for more information on CEH check this link http://www.eccouncil.org/certification/certified_ethical_hacker.aspx&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 18:42:58 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/27/ec-council-ceh-unethical-behavior.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/27/ec-council-ceh-unethical-behavior.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WPScan 1.1 released</title>
        
          <description>I am pleased to announce, after 5 months of work, that WPScan version 1.1 has been released!

With 780 more lines of code the most notable changes are:

Detection for 750 more plugins.
Detection for 107 new plugin vulnerabilities.
Detection for 447 possible timthumb file locations.
Advanced version fingerprinting implemented.
Full Path Disclosure (FPD) checks.
Auto updates.
Progress indicators.
Improved custom 404 checking.
Improved plugin detection.
Improved error_log checking.
Lots of bugs fixed.
Lots of small tweaks.

A full list of changes can be found here:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/wpscan/source/browse/trunk/CHANGELOG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/wpscan/source/browse/trunk/CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 13:32:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/25/wpscan-1-1-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/25/wpscan-1-1-released.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress 'In the Wild' and WPScan Update</title>
        
          <description>As part of my on-going interest in WordPress security I wanted to find out for myself what the state of security was like on installations in the wild.

A list of servers running WordPress was acquired from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodanhq.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shodan&lt;/a&gt; by searching for a particular HTTP response header and its value. The list contained 10,000 entries, I don't know for sure, but I assume the list contained servers from around the world and was fairly random.

An Open Source project I have been working on, &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/wpscan/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WPScan&lt;/a&gt;, a WordPress security scanner, was used to passively scan 100 of those WordPress installations. This was done partly to test the scanner for any defects and also to gather data about the security of WordPress installations in the wild.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 01:36:47 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/23/wordpress-in-the-wild-and-wpscan-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/11/23/wordpress-in-the-wild-and-wpscan-update.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Full Path Disclosure (FPD)</title>
        
          <description>Many people including developers, vendors and security professionals believe that Full Path Disclosure (FPD) is mainly a Security Misconfiguration problem rather than a Input Sanitation or Error Handling problem. I'm not saying that they are wrong, but I hope to convince them that it is more of a coding bug than a configuration bug. I want to put my argument over as to why I think FPD is a bug in source code and not in configuration. 

&lt;strong&gt;What is Full Path Disclosure (FPD)?&lt;/strong&gt;

According to OWASP:
&quot;Full Path Disclosure (FPD) vulnerabilities enable the attacker to see the path to the webroot/file. e.g.: /home/omg/htdocs/file/. Certain vulnerabilities, such as using the load_file() (within a SQL Injection) query to view the page source, require the attacker to have the full path to the file they wish to view.&quot;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Full_Path_Disclosure&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Full_Path_Disclosure&lt;/a&gt;

For me this is a very vague description of what FPD really is. FPD occurs when a web application encounters an error that is displayed to the user; the error includes the full path to the file the error occurred in possibly along with other debugging information.

&lt;strong&gt;Why is it a problem?&lt;/strong&gt;

It's just the path of the file from the root directory, what's all the fuss about?

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 15:19:45 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/10/05/full-path-disclosure-fpd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/10/05/full-path-disclosure-fpd.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Concrete5 &lt;= 5.4.2.1 SQL Injection and XSS Vulnerabilities</title>
        
          <description># Exploit Title: Concrete5 &lt; = 5.4.2.1 SQL Injection and XSS Vulnerabilities
# Date: 2011-10-04
# Author: Ryan Dewhurst (ryandewhurst at gmail) (@ethicalhack3r)(www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk)
# Software Link: http://sourceforge.net/projects/concretecms/files/concrete5/5.4.2.1/
# Version: 5.4.2.1 (tested)

1.Vulnerability Description

Multiple SQL Injection, Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) and Information Disclosure vulnerabilities were identified within Concrete5 version 5.4.2.1

Please note: Only a select few vulnerabilities are outlined in this disclosure, many other vulnerabilities were discovered. Due to time restraints only a small sample of the vulnerabilities are outlined below. The vendor was contacted and replied promptly. Further assistance was asked for but not delivered due to my time constraints.

2.Software Description

CMS made for Marketing but built for Geeks, concrete5 [0] is a content management system that is free and open source.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 13:52:06 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/10/04/concrete5.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/10/04/concrete5.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Video] WPScan and Metasploit's Meterpreter</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Video demonstrating the PoC of WPScan using Metasploit's meterpreter to exploit a vulnerable WordPress plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/29660886?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/29660886&quot;&gt;WPScan and Metasploit's Meterpreter&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user8685865&quot;&gt;ryan dewhurst&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 15:10:56 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/27/video-wpscan-and-metasploits-meterpreter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/27/video-wpscan-and-metasploits-meterpreter.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[ES] Metasploit db_autopwn contra Windows 8</title>
        
          <description>Mi primer blog post en Español! &lt;em&gt;(lo siento si mi Español escrito no es perfecto)&lt;/em&gt;

Ayer (o el anterior) Microsoft hizo disponible &quot;Windows 8 Developer Preview&quot; para cualquier persona poder descargar. Yo hize la instalación en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualbox.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; siguiendo este &lt;a href=&quot;http://geekswithblogs.net/RollingIT/archive/2011/09/14/getting-hands-on-with-virtual-machine-of-windows-8.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guía&lt;/a&gt; (en Ingles).

Quería ver si Microsoft posiblemente han usado algunas librerías/programas de versiones de Windows antiguos que posiblemente tengan vulnerabilidades remotos y que el &lt;a href=&quot;http://metasploit.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Metesploit&lt;/a&gt; tenga un exploit para el.

Para esto quería usar el db_autopwn para que Metasploit use todos los exploits que tenga para los puertos que Windows 8 Developer tenga abierto. Al mismo ves será un test rápido y sencillo.

&lt;em&gt;(Configuración para BT5 R1, usando Metasploit revision 13728)&lt;/em&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 18:12:24 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/14/es-metasploit-db_autopwn-contra-windows-8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/14/es-metasploit-db_autopwn-contra-windows-8.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Setting up Tor on BackTrack</title>
        
          <description>I was playing around with getting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randomstorm.com/wpscan-security-tool.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wpscan&lt;/a&gt; to run through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.torproject.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; network so I needed to setup Tor (from source) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.privoxy.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Privoxy&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BackTrack&lt;/a&gt;. These are the steps I took to setup Tor and Privoxy on Backtrack 5 R1. (wpscan does not yet support scanning through the Tor network)

I am no Tor expert and there are probably easier/better ways of doing this.

&lt;strong&gt;Installing Tor (Anonymous SOCKS proxy):&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
$apt-get install libssl-dev
$wget https://www.torproject.org/dist/tor-0.2.2.32.tar.gz
$tar -xzvf tor-0.2.2.32.tar.gz
$cd tor-0.2.2.32
$chmod +x configure
$./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; src/or/tor
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 18:33:59 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/08/setting-up-tor-on-backtrack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/09/08/setting-up-tor-on-backtrack.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress CD</title>
        
          <description>I needed a research environment to help develop &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randomstorm.com/wpscan-security-tool.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WPScan&lt;/a&gt; so I put together a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualbox.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; virtual machine with every &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/download/release-archive/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress release&lt;/a&gt; installed (not including MU or BETA/Candidates). The download, untar and database creation was all automated. The manual bit was installing them all.

&lt;strong&gt;Installed are the following versions of Wordpress:&lt;/strong&gt;
wordpress-0.71-gold
wordpress-1.0-platinum
wordpress-1.0.1-miles
wordpress-1.0.2-blakey
wordpress-1.2-delta
wordpress-1.2-mingus
wordpress-1.2.1
wordpress-1.2.2
wordpress-1.5-strayhorn
wordpress-1.5.1.1
wordpress-1.5.1.2
wordpress-1.5.1.3
wordpress-1.5.1
wordpress-1.5.2
wordpress-2.0.1
wordpress-2.0.10
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 19:35:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/07/13/wordpress-cd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/07/13/wordpress-cd.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BSidesLondon HNN Videos</title>
        
          <description>20th of April 2011 was the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securitybsides.com/w/page/12194156/FrontPage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BSides&lt;/a&gt; held in London, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securitybsides.com/w/page/27749044/BSidesLondon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BSidesLondon&lt;/a&gt;.

Before the event I had been speaking to Space Rouge of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackernews.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HNN&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/hnncast-boxee/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;getting HNN content on Boxee&lt;/a&gt;. I said I would be attending BSidesLondon and volunteered my time to do some recording for them. This would involve some 'promos', interviews and general conference footage.

I was working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infosec.co.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;InfoSecurity&lt;/a&gt; Europe 2011 on the same day. My boss had kindly allowed me to attend the first half of BSidesLondon as long as I worked the second half of the day at InfoSecurity Europe.

After BSidesLondon I sent my footage to HNN for them to edit into an episode of 'Behind the Firewall'. I asked on a couple of occasions if they had chance to put an episode together out of my footage. The last time I asked, last week, I was told that HNN would be shutting down and that my footage would not be used.

Instead of letting the footage go to waste I thought I would stick the &lt;strong&gt;unedited&lt;/strong&gt; interviews on YouTube and share them with you all.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 22:44:31 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/07/10/bsideslondon-hnn-videos.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/07/10/bsideslondon-hnn-videos.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Did lulzsec expose your friends password?</title>
        
          <description>I assume you have all heard about Lulzsec over the past few months so I will not go into their backstory and instead get straight to the point.

Yesterday, 26th June 2011, they released their last data dump on ThePirateBay (TPB) containing usernames and passwords from a few different sources. One of those sources was hackforums.net, I myself had registered here once upon a time. Luckily I had signed up with a disposable password. It turns out however that, yes, that password was leaked in the final lulzsec data dump.

The data dump has now been removed from TPB due to some of the files allegedly being infected with malware. So I found this site which allows you to search for your email address to see if you may have been effected; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dazzlepod.com/lulzsec/final/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://dazzlepod.com/lulzsec/final/&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 01:45:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/27/did-lulzsec-expose-your-freinds-password.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/27/did-lulzsec-expose-your-freinds-password.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Introducing WPScan - WordPress Security Scanner</title>
        
          <description>After creating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/wordpress-brute-force-tool/&quot;&gt;WordPress Brute Force Tool&lt;/a&gt; last weekend, I decided to create a bigger project out of it, called WPScan. 

WPScan is a black box WordPress Security Scanner written in Ruby which attempts to find known security weaknesses within WordPress installations. Its intended use it to be for security professionals or WordPress administrators to asses the security posture of their WordPress installations. The code base is Open Source and licensed under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GPLv3&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;strong&gt;Features include:&lt;/strong&gt;

Username enumeration
Weak password cracking (multithreaded)
Version enumeration
Vulnerability enumeration (based on version)
Plugin enumeration &lt;del datetime=&quot;2013-01-29T14:40:27+00:00&quot;&gt;(todo)&lt;/del&gt;
Plugin vulnerability enumeration (based on version) &lt;del datetime=&quot;2013-01-29T14:40:27+00:00&quot;&gt;(todo)&lt;/del&gt;
Other miscellaneous checks

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 15:29:01 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/16/introducing-wpscan-wordpress-security-scanner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/16/introducing-wpscan-wordpress-security-scanner.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress Brute Force Tool</title>
        
          <description>Following on from my previous post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/patching-wordpress-username-disclosure/&quot;&gt;Patching WordPress Username Disclosure&lt;/a&gt; I got bored over the weekend and decided to implement Veronica Valeros's username disclosure technique into a WordPress password brute force tool.

It is nothing revolutionary or difficult to code, but it may come in handy one day on a pentest or web application assessment, mainly to automate the process.

Currently you can use the tool in 3 different ways.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 15:36:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/13/wordpress-brute-force-tool.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/13/wordpress-brute-force-tool.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Patching WordPress Username Disclosure</title>
        
          <description>On May 26th Veronica Valero of Talsoft S.R.L. posted a security advisory on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://seclists.org/fulldisclosure/2011/May/493&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Full Disclosure&lt;/a&gt; mailing list outlining a username disclosure vulnerability via a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2010-A4-Insecure_Direct_Object_References&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Direct Object Reference&lt;/a&gt;. 

This is a problem in itself, however, what was more interesting to me was Zerial's &lt;a href=&quot;http://seclists.org/fulldisclosure/2011/May/494&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; to the advisory; 

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Also you can &quot;enumerate&quot; wordpress users using the wp-login.php. Whenyou enter a non-existent user wordpress returns &quot;Invalid username&quot; andwhen you enter a valid user with any random/dummie password, wordpressreturns &quot;Invalid Password&quot;. Now you can use brute-force to enumerate allvalid users using, for example, a name&amp;username dictionary.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 16:38:30 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/01/patching-wordpress-username-disclosure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/06/01/patching-wordpress-username-disclosure.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ethical Hacking Degrees - the good, the bad, the ugly</title>
        
          <description>&lt;rant&gt;
I often get emails (yes, people actually email me) around September time from young students who have come across this blog wanting to know more about doing Ethical Hacking at university level. I am writing this blog post in part to prevent myself from asking these young people for money for my time in replying to all of their questions. Also there seems to be a lot of misinformation about doing degrees related to computer/information security within the community.

Now, you maybe thinking... Ryan has invested countless thousands of pounds and four years of his life to his Ethical Hacking degree so he is bound to be biased. Well, I guess if I wasn't a little biased then I wouldn't be human, but I am going to try to be as honest as possible.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 22:09:40 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/04/11/ethical-hacking-degrees-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/04/11/ethical-hacking-degrees-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>HNNCast + Boxee = &lt;3</title>
        
          <description>Trying to get &quot;hacker&quot; media on Boxee can sometimes be a pain in the ass. 

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/g2834.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;g2834&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1127&quot; /&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:35:52 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/04/01/hnncast-boxee.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/04/01/hnncast-boxee.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DO NOT CLICK!</title>
        
          <description>So I was listening to the latest PaulDotCom security weekly podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://pauldotcom.com/2011/02/pauldotcom---security-weekly---48.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;episode 232&lt;/a&gt; via my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/securitypodcasts-boxee-app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SecurityPodcasts Boxee app&lt;/a&gt; where Mike Murr or Murray or both?! were talking about effective Phishing and how to be 110% successful.

My phishing experience is minimal so I decided to find out for myself how easy it was to get people to click on 'malicious' hyperlinks. I did this by tweeting the following from my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ethicalhack3r&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ethicalhack3r&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account.

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-28-at-11.40.24.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-28-at-11.40.24.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Screen shot 2011-02-28 at 11.40.24&quot; width=&quot;310&quot; height=&quot;125&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-876&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&quot;DO NOT CLICK =&gt; http://bit.ly/eIC1Y2&quot;

As you can see I tweeted the words &quot;DO NOT CLICK =&gt;&quot; followed by a shortened bit.ly hyperlink. I suspect that most of my (at the time of writing) 3000 followers are in some way interested in information security and are all well aware of the potential risks of clicking unknown shortened hyperlinks. Or so you would think.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 13:10:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/02/28/do-not-click.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/02/28/do-not-click.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Grepping for bugs in PHP</title>
        
          <description>Today I used the following commands to grep through PHP source code to find some bugs. I thought they may be useful to someone else so I thought I would stick them on here. This list is by no means extensive however they are the ones I found most useful. 

&lt;strong&gt;Find user input/output for possible XSS:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;grep -i -r &quot;echo&quot; *
grep -i -r &quot;\$_GET&quot; *
grep -i -r &quot;\$_&quot; * | grep &quot;echo&quot;
grep -i -r &quot;\$_GET&quot; * | grep &quot;echo&quot;
grep -i -r &quot;\$_POST&quot; * | grep &quot;echo&quot;
grep -i -r &quot;\$_REQUEST&quot; * | grep &quot;echo&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 16:40:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/02/01/greping-for-bugs-in-php.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/02/01/greping-for-bugs-in-php.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Web Application Security Timeline (WAST) v1.0</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to know where we’re going, we have to understand where we have come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I had the idea of creating the Web Application Security Timeline (WAST) and posted an RFC yesterday in this post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/web-application-security-timeline-rfc/&quot;&gt;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/web-application-security-timeline-rfc/&lt;/a&gt;. After much feedback from the WebAppSec community from various mailing lists, Twitter, email and this blog I present to you version 1.0!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This timeline was created by Ryan Dewhurst from the accumulation of feedback from the WebAppSec community to visualise and allow others to visualise the significant events in the short history of web application security. This image holds no copyright or has any restrictions of use, think of this image as yours and do as you wish with it. If you believe that any of the information on the timeline is incorrect or have any other feedback on improvements please email ryandewhurst-A-gmail.com with the subject of 'wast'.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Application Security Timeline (WAST) v1.0&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/WAST_v1.0.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/WAST_v1.0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;WAST_v1.0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-854&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 17:11:57 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/10/web-application-security-timeline-wast-v1-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/10/web-application-security-timeline-wast-v1-0.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Web Application Security Timeline RFC</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to know where we’re going, we have to understand where we have come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began wondering a couple of days ago, how did we get here? What was the evolution of web application security? To answer this question I decided to put together a Web Application Security Timeline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timeline I present to you today is just a start, I hope to make it more comprehensive with feedback from the community. So I ask for your comments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the most significant events in the short history of web application security?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is missing from the timeline?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you improve it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Application Security Timeline DRAFT&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/timeline_draft.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/timeline_draft.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;timeline_draft&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-847&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 13:23:01 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/09/web-application-security-timeline-rfc.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/09/web-application-security-timeline-rfc.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Barclays bank #fail</title>
        
          <description>Look what I saw in a Barclays bank window during my trip to Gibraltar! PCI Fail?

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC01990.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/DSC01990.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;DSC01990&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-840&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 14:17:36 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/03/barclays-bank-fail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2011/01/03/barclays-bank-fail.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Persistent BeEF</title>
        
          <description>No, not that kind of beef!

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/there-is-no-such-thing-as-mad-cow-disease-300x236.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;there-is-no-such-thing-as-mad-cow-disease&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;236&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-820&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;BeEF is a browser exploitation framework. This tool will demonstrate the collecting of zombie browsers and browser vulnerabilities in real-time. It provides a command and control interface which facilitates the targeting of individual or groups of zombie browsers.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bindshell.net/tools/beef/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.bindshell.net/tools/beef/&lt;/a&gt;

BeEF is a tool used to enhance the exploitation of Cross Site Scripting (XSS) attacks by providing a complete and easy to use exploitation framework. It currently sports Metasploit integration, keylogging, port scanning, TOR detection and many other cool features. You no longer have an excuse to fill your reports with 'XSS' pop-up boxes!

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 15:42:06 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/11/05/persistent-beef.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/11/05/persistent-beef.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP AppSec Ireland 2010</title>
        
          <description>Over the weekend I attended OWASP AppSec Ireland 2010 at Trinity College in Dublin. The event was a full day event held on the 17th September starting at 9AM and 'officially' ending at 9PM. On my first night in Dublin I went for an excellent Italian meal with some great people, these include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/securityninja&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@securityninja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/Angelill0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@Angelill0, &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/danielcornell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@danielcornell&lt;/a&gt; and others. The evening was polished off with a traditional pint of Guiness in a local pub.

On the day of the conference I arrived a little early and had some brief discussions with a couple of the attendees. The conference kicked off with the keynote talk by John Viega titled &quot;Application Security in the Real World&quot;. This was an excellent talk that put into perspective the reality of application security within business. The keynote was followed by a brief unplanned summary by Samy Kamkar on his talk which he is touring Europe with. I look forward to seeing his full talk at BruCON next weekend.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 17:32:28 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/09/19/owasp-appsec-ireland-2010.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/09/19/owasp-appsec-ireland-2010.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DVWA 1.0.7 is here!</title>
        
          <description>After 9 months since the last release we are proud to present the all new Damn Vulnerable Web Application version 1.0.7.

&lt;strong&gt;What's new?&lt;/strong&gt;
The vulnerability help page has been improved.
We now display the logged on username along with the vulnerability level and php-ids status.
Blind SQL injection has been implemented.
We now have official documentation.
You can now compare all vulnerable source code in one page with the 'view all' button.
The whole theme has been redesigned, including a new great looking logo.
Many bug fixes and small changes throughout the application.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 23:28:42 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/09/08/dvwa-1-0-7-is-here.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/09/08/dvwa-1-0-7-is-here.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DropBox Security</title>
        
          <description>For those of you new to Dropbox:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Dropbox is a Web-based file hosting service operated by Dropbox, Inc. which uses cloud computing to enable users to store and share files and folders with others across the Internet using file synchronization.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dropbox_%28service%29&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dropbox_%28service%29&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/Dropbox-150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Dropbox&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-757&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Dropbox has become very popular and widely used as it has so many different uses and makes file sharing over the internet easy. Dropbox allows you to make public image galleries, share files publicly, share files between computers and manage version control. All this straight from your file system. I like to think of it as git or a subversion repository with a nice interface. 

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 14:29:06 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/08/03/dropbox-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/08/03/dropbox-security.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Interview] The Jester</title>
        
          <description>It's not often I interview people for the blog however when some one catches my eye and raises my interest I like to find out more about them and share it with my readers. This time I interviewed 'The Jester'. The Jester has been in the media spotlight recently for taking down Jihadist terrorist web sites via use of a targeted DoS attacks. 

&lt;strong&gt;* Can you tell us a little bit about yourself and what you do?&lt;/strong&gt;

Ryan, I would like to give you and your readers a little more about me but it's kind of difficult to do that, given the nature of my targets, all I can give you sir is what's already 'out there' - I am ex-mil - and slightly pissed at the surge in Jihadist online activities.

Now with regard to what I do: I aim to cause disruption to the online efforts of Jihadists on the internet. They have realized that they can recruit, train and coordinate home-grown terrorists completely via the internet, without ever having to meet. This cuts out much of the risk associated with any face-to-face contact for the recruiters. Web recruitment targets young, tech-savvy, vulnerable Muslims, the iPod generation if you like. By making these sites unreliable, the potential recruit numbers start to dwindle. I limit my hits to defined time-slots (rather than killing them completely) because I am well aware that official Counter Terrorist Agencies use some of these sites for intelligence gathering. I have been asked why I DON'T hit certain sites, well it's simple. By NOT hitting certain sites (and hitting others hard) I am 'herding', people give up easily when a site is constantly up and down, and move on to a more reliable one. So it creates a funnel-effect, funneling terrorists and potential terrorists away from peripheral sites and into a smaller space that is easier to monitor.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2010 00:35:19 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/07/04/interview-the-jester.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/07/04/interview-the-jester.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Johnny Can’t Pentest</title>
        
          <description>A white paper released recently (not dated) by the University of California titled ‘Why Johnny Can’t Pentest: An Analysis of Black-box Web Vulnerability Scanners’ evaluates eleven commercial and open-source black-box web vulnerability scanners.

The three authors of the paper (Adoupe, Marco, Vigna) test the black-box scanners against their custom vulnerable web application they called WackoPicko. Their custom web application contained a number of different technical and business logic vulnerabilities, both authenticated and un-authenticated. 

They tested each scanner against WackoPicko in three different modes. Initial (point-and-click), Config (login credentials/mechanism provided) and Manual (local proxy use). The eleven scanners tested were Acunetix, Appscan, Burp, Grendel-Scan, Hailstorm, Milescan, N-Stalker, NTOSpider, Paros, w3af and Webinspect.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 17:48:40 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/07/03/738.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/07/03/738.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Web server zombies</title>
        
          <description>Every now and then I like to visit black-hat community forums for a number of legitimate reasons. I like to see what the other side are up to, what they are buying/selling, at what price, who they are targeting, the skill level of the attackers, what exploitation techniques they use, etc. Visiting these underground community forums passively can be a great learning experience.

I had read stories about servers or web servers more specifically being targeted over personal computers for their use in DDoS attacks. Using a server rather than a client as a zombie means that the attackers have higher bandwidth,  RAM, CPU and other resources at their disposal. Servers are generally more secure than clients as you would expect the people who set them up and manage them have a greater awareness of the risks involved. Although servers are generally more difficult to compromise, compromising 100 servers may be worth more than 1000 clients.

While browsing a particular black-hat community forum I came across a post by a user who wanted to purchase compromised web servers and made a particular request that the servers should have his supplied PHP script pre-uploaded.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 22:21:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/06/27/web-server-zombies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/06/27/web-server-zombies.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Weponising Web bugs</title>
        
          <description>Back in March 2009 I wrote a blog post about using web bugs in information gathering, found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/security/using-a-web-bug-for-information-gathering/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For those unfamiliar with web bugs;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;A web bug is an object that is embedded in a web page  or e-mail  and is usually invisible to the user but allows checking that a user has viewed the page or e-mail. One common use is in e-mail tracking. Alternative names are web beacon, tracking bug, tracking pixel, pixel tag, 1×1 gif, and clear gif.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug&lt;/a&gt;

At the time I thought I had stumbled across something unique and that no one had really understood the implications of allowing the posting of remote images in web applications. The idea originally came to me when playing around with Adrian Crenshaw's (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irongeek.com/&quot;&gt;IronGeek&lt;/a&gt;) logo. I wasn't aware of the term 'web bug' so I explained to Adrian my concept, he knew what a web bug was and seemed to be well aware of their consequences.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 17:27:12 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/31/weponising-web-bugs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/31/weponising-web-bugs.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DevBUG - Keeping track so you don't have to</title>
        
          <description>DevBUG is an idea that came to me while conducting a Vulnerability Assessment for University a few months back. We did a service scan on a web server and found that way too many ports and services were running! But that wasn't the problem, well, not for us anyway. The problem was, is that we had 20 different software services and versions to google and write about.

So what is the process? We needed to find the software package's homepage, find what the latest version of the package is for the development tree that was used, find out how old the version the web server was running was and then try to find any known vulnerabilities associated with that version. This is not too much hassle when you have to do it one to three times however when you have to do it twenty to fifty times it starts to become time consuming.

So in comes DevBUG. DevBUG is a web application which will be free for any one to use, no subscriptions or anything. It will be a search engine for software packages and their versions. Three times a day (every 8 hours) starting at 8AM GMT a backed spider will visit every software package's homepage looking for new versions, if it finds a new version this will be added to a database. So the idea is, to keep a record of software, their released versions, release dates and any vulnerabilities which may affect each version. So this is great to solve our original problem! We have a one stop shop for all the information we need! But what other uses does it have?

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 17:05:21 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/21/devbug-keeping-track-so-you-dont-have-to.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/21/devbug-keeping-track-so-you-dont-have-to.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>UK Security Clearance 101</title>
        
          <description>In the Information Security industry it is said that if you have security clearance you can earn significantly more income and work on exiting secret projects for government agencies. So what is security clearance and how do I get it?

Security clearance is a way to prove your trustworthiness at a particular point in time so that you can work with sensitive information on government projects. Your trustworthiness is assessed by a thorough background check. There are a number of different security clearance levels depending on the sensitivity of the information which you are required to work with. These levels were changed in the UK during WWII to reflect those of the US so that sensitive information could be shared and the sensitivity of the information not be confused.

&lt;strong&gt;National Security Clearances:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developed Vetting (DV) &lt;/strong&gt;
This is the highest level of Security Clearance and is required for people with substantial unsupervised access to TOP SECRET assets, or for working in the intelligence or security agencies. This level of clearance involves Security Check (SC) and, in addition, completion of a (DV) questionnaire, financial checks, checking of references and a detailed interview with a vetting officer. To gain (DV) clearance you will normally have had to have been a resident in the UK for a minimum of 10 years.
 
&lt;strong&gt;Security Check (SC)&lt;/strong&gt; is for people who have substantial access to SECRET, or occasional access to TOP SECRET assets and information. This level of clearance involves a (BPSS) check plus UK criminal and security checks and a credit check. To gain (SC) clearance you will normally have had to have been a resident in the UK for a minimum of 5 years.

&lt;strong&gt;Counter Terrorist Check (CTC)&lt;/strong&gt; is required for personnel whose work involves close proximity to public figures, gives access to information or material vulnerable to terrorist attack or involves unrestricted access to certain government or commercial establishments. A (CTC) does not allow access, or knowledge, or custody, of protectively marked assets and information. The check includes a Baseline Personnel Security Standard Check (BPSS) and also a check against national security records. To gain (CTC) clearance you will normally have had to have been a resident in the UK for a minimum of 3 years.

&lt;strong&gt;Baseline Personnel Security Standard (BPSS)&lt;/strong&gt; (formally Basic Check)and Enhanced Baseline Standard (EBS) (formerly Enhanced Basic Check or Basic Check +): These are not formal security clearances; they are a package of pre-employment checks that represent good recruitment and employment practice.
A BPSS or EBS aims to provide an appropriate level of assurance as to the trustworthiness, integrity, and probable reliability of prospective employees.  The check is carried out by screening identity documents and references.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

Reference: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securityclearedjobs.com/HowToBeSecurityCleared.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.securityclearedjobs.com/HowToBeSecurityCleared.aspx&lt;/a&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 15:16:10 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/16/uk-security-clearance-101.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/05/16/uk-security-clearance-101.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Month of PHP Security</title>
        
          <description>In 2007 the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hardened-php.net/&quot;&gt;Hardened-PHP Project&lt;/a&gt; setup by three German Security Researchers organised the Month of PHP Bugs (MOPB). The 'Month of Bugs' concept was started by non other than HD Moore back in 2006 with his Month of Browser Bugs (MoBB) which found security holes within most of the popular browsers. Since then there have been many 'Month's of Bugs' including &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.info-pull.com/mokb/&quot;&gt;Month of Kernel Bugs (MoKB)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.info-pull.com/moab/&quot;&gt;Month of Apple Bugs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitpwn.com/&quot;&gt;Month of Twitter Bugs&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://theharmonyguy.com/2009/09/15/the-month-of-facebook-bugs-halfway-report/&quot;&gt;Month of Facebook Bugs&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;strong&gt;So why a Month of Bugs?&lt;/strong&gt;
&quot;The intention of the Month of PHP Security is to gather the best research and articles about PHP security topics from the security community and share them with the rest of the world. This time the goal is not only to improve the security of PHP itself and applications directly by fixing security bugs, but also to help PHP developers around the world to write better and more secure PHP applications.&quot;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 15:29:34 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/04/28/month-of-php-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/04/28/month-of-php-security.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Skipfish - Automated web security scanner</title>
        
          <description>A couple of days ago (March 19th) Michal Zalewski famous for tools such as p0f and his excellent book 'Silence on the wire' announced the release of an open source automated web security scanner called Skipfish from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://googleonlinesecurity.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Google Online Security Blog&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/sf_name.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;sf_name&quot; width=&quot;203&quot; height=&quot;93&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-638&quot; /&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Key features:

&lt;strong&gt;High speed:&lt;/strong&gt; pure C code, highly optimized HTTP handling, minimal CPU footprint - easily achieving 2000 requests per second with responsive targets. 

&lt;strong&gt;Ease of use:&lt;/strong&gt; heuristics to support a variety of quirky web frameworks and mixed-technology sites, with automatic learning capabilities, on-the-fly wordlist creation, and form autocompletion. 

&lt;strong&gt;Cutting-edge security logic:&lt;/strong&gt; high quality, low false positive, differential security checks, capable of spotting a range of subtle flaws, including blind injection vectors. &lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 03:49:44 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/03/21/skipfish-automated-web-security-scanner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/03/21/skipfish-automated-web-security-scanner.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Testing Methodology</title>
        
          <description>It is very easy for some one to find an XSS vulnerability within a web application and write a report about it. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehatsec.com/home/assets/WPStatsreport_100107.pdf&quot;&gt;WhiteHat Security&lt;/a&gt; (2007) there is a 73% chance that you will find an XSS vulnerability within a web application. Does finding one of these mean you have assessed the security of the web application? Let's take a web application vulnerability that is 'seen' to be more critical. Again, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehatsec.com/home/assets/WPStatsreport_100107.pdf&quot;&gt;WhiteHat Security&lt;/a&gt; you have a 18% likelihood to find an SQL Injection vulnerability within a web application. So during the web application security assessment you have found an SQL injection vulnerability, the back end DBMS is a version of Microsoft SQL Server which has '&lt;a href=&quot;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms175046.aspx&quot;&gt;xp_cmdshell&lt;/a&gt;' enabled by default. You manage to get a reverse shell and acquire a copy of the database. Great! By gaining shell access to the server does that mean you have properly assessed the security of the web application? No!

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 14:47:38 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/03/08/owasp-testing-methodology.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/03/08/owasp-testing-methodology.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WordPress &gt;= 2.9 Failure to Restrict URL Access</title>
        
          <description>1. *Advisory Information*

Title: WordPress &amp;gt;= 2.9 Failure to Restrict URL Access
Date published: 13/02/2010

2. *Vulnerability Information*

Class: Failure to Restrict URL Access
Remotely Exploitable: Yes
Locally Exploitable: Yes

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2010 19:23:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/02/13/wordpress-2-9-failure-to-restrict-url-access.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/02/13/wordpress-2-9-failure-to-restrict-url-access.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Writing reports - Oh noes!</title>
        
          <description>Report writing has a bad reputation, every one seems to hate writing them and believe it to be the anticlimax of the assessment process. I haven't been writing reports for very long, the reports that I have written I have enjoyed, no doubt in time the novelty will wear off and I will grow to hate them too. There are however lessons that I have learnt in my short report writing experience which I believe could have made my report writing that little bit easier and less time consuming. Those lessons I am going to share with you and if your just starting out in your report writing duties hopefully these can help you too. Or if your a report writing guru share your tips with me! The reports I have written are mainly web application assessments so I will concentrate on those.

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/524568722_609668d9a0-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;524568722_609668d9a0&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-555&quot; /&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 19:44:06 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/30/writing-reports-oh-noes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/30/writing-reports-oh-noes.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ethical Hacking / Security University Degrees UK</title>
        
          <description>One of the most popular posts on my blog is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/2009/04/29/guest-post-current-available-uk-degrees/&quot;&gt;Guest post: Current Available UK Degrees&lt;/a&gt; by 1337speak in April last year. I have decided to update the list as to keep the information up to date.

You who know me will know that I my self am enrolled on one of these University courses. I believe that if you're starting out in security and want to make a career out of it this may be the best place to start. For me the course has done wonders, not only in what I have learnt however the people I've met and the drive it has given me to succeed in my chosen career.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 01:11:11 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/25/ethical-hacking-security-university-degrees-uk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/25/ethical-hacking-security-university-degrees-uk.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>SecurityPodcasts Boxee App</title>
        
          <description>&lt;strong&gt;What is Boxee?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Boxee is the best way to enjoy entertainment from the Internet and computer on your TV&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boxee.tv/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.boxee.tv/&lt;/a&gt;

Boxee allows you to develop 'Apps' which are basically XML files which grab RSS feeds. These Apps can be installed through remote repositorys. To truncate and combine all the security podcasts I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://pipes.yahoo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yahoo! Pipes&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/securitypodcast_thumb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;securitypodcast_thumb&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-532&quot; /&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 21:05:33 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/19/securitypodcasts-boxee-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/19/securitypodcasts-boxee-app.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dionaea - Low interaction honeypot</title>
        
          <description>After running Glastopf (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/2010/01/10/glastopf-web-application-honeypot/&quot;&gt;Glastopf – Web Application Honeypot&lt;/a&gt;) for a few days and not getting any hits, I was a bit disappointed. I speculate that maybe you need to give web application honeypots more time to propagate across the Internet and get picked up by search engines to receive any significant hits, or even give the honeypot its own domain name. From my earlier post you will notice that I had tried to get Dionaea to run first.

Markus the lead developer of Dionaea got in contact after he read my post and saw that I was having trouble getting it running. It turned out to be a complete fail on my part, after following the instructions on the Dionaea &lt;a href=&quot;http://dionaea.carnivore.it/&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;, Dionaea installed perfectly fine, it was just a case of me not knowing how to run it properly.

&lt;strong&gt;What is Dionaea?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Dionaea is meant to be a nepenthes successor, embedding python as scripting language, using libemu to detect shellcodes, supporting ipv6 and tls&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Dionaea intention is to trap malware exploiting vulnerabilities exposed by services offerd to a network, the ultimate goal is gaining a copy of the malware.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 20:34:26 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/17/dionaea-low-interaction-honeypot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/17/dionaea-low-interaction-honeypot.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Glastopf - Web Application Honeypot</title>
        
          <description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/glastopf.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;glastopf&quot; width=&quot;204&quot; height=&quot;83&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-497&quot; /&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

I bought an old battered PC over the weekend with the goal of installing a honeypot. I had never installed a honeypot before so wasn't quite sure what to expect. At first I decided on &lt;a href=&quot;http://dionaea.carnivore.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dionaea&lt;/a&gt; the succsesor to Nepenthes, I had heard great things about Nepenthes from a friend of mine (&lt;a href=&quot;http://infosanity.wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Infosanity&lt;/a&gt;). After going through the installation process, I couldn't get Dionaea to 'make' with the right Python version detected (&gt; 3.0), after about an hour of playing around I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;http://glastopf.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glastopf&lt;/a&gt; a try.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 20:08:39 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/10/glastopf-web-application-honeypot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/10/glastopf-web-application-honeypot.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>I got ha ha hacked</title>
        
          <description>I had a security breach on the blog over the Christmas period. To cut a long story short two black hats named HcJ and cyb3r-1st compromised another site on the shared hosting server, they decided to deface my blogs for a short period of time while they were at it. After talking to both of them regarding the breach it turns out they are nice guys (a bit misguided), they told me how they breached the server so that I could pass the information on to the hosting provider for them to patch it.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/hacked1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/hacked1-300x298.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;hacked1&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-493&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 22:55:35 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/02/i-got-ha-ha-hacked.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/02/i-got-ha-ha-hacked.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Free software in a Windowed world</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded to Windows 7 from Vista. I had planned to migrate fully to Ubuntu 9.10 Karmic however after nearly £100 investment in wireless equipment and none of the hardware working under Ubuntu I bit the bullet. I will now be running Ubuntu and other Linux distributions as Virtual Machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list (in no particular order) of essential (to me) Open Source and Free (as in beer) software (non-security) I installed on my shinny new Windows 7:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FileZilla FTP client - &lt;a href=&quot;http://filezilla-project.org/&quot;&gt;http://filezilla-project.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Souce)&lt;br /&gt;
Mozilla Thunderbird - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozillamessaging.com&quot;&gt;http://www.mozillamessaging.com&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Inkscape - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inkscape.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.inkscape.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
BitTorrent - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bittorrent.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.bittorrent.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Wireshark - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.wireshark.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
7-Zip - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.7-zip.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.7-zip.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Notepad++ - &lt;a href=&quot;http://notepad-plus.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;http://notepad-plus.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Mozilla Firefox - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/&quot;&gt;http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
OpenOffice - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openoffice.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.openoffice.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Sun VirtualBox - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.virtualbox.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Tortoise SVN - &lt;a href=&quot;http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/&quot;&gt;http://tortoisesvn.tigris.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
VLC - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/&quot;&gt;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
TrueCrypt - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.truecrypt.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.truecrypt.org/&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
XAMPP - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apachefriends.org/en/xampp.html&quot;&gt;http://www.apachefriends.org/en/xampp.html&lt;/a&gt; (Open Source)&lt;br /&gt;
Zattoo - &lt;a href=&quot;http://zattoo.com/&quot;&gt;http://zattoo.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Free)&lt;br /&gt;
Spotify - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spotify.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.spotify.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Free)&lt;br /&gt;
Skype - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skype.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.skype.com/&lt;/a&gt; (Free)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should now be easier than ever to pwn my box now that you all know what software and OS I'm running. ;) What Open Source/Free software can you not live without?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. HAPPY NEW YEEAARRR!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 23:15:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/01/free-software-in-a-windowed-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2010/01/01/free-software-in-a-windowed-world.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>RandomStorm acquire DVWA</title>
        
          <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randomstorm.com/&quot;&gt;RandomStorm&lt;/a&gt; have acquired Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA) :)

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

RandomStorm showed their interest in DVWA and wanted to help the project grow. After some weeks of talks we have settled on an agreement which I believe will benefit the DVWA project immensely. 

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

What do RandomStorm do?

&lt;blockquote&gt;RandomStorm was formed in 2007 to provide a proactive vulnerability management service for companies and organisations that take network security seriously and need to demonstrate maximum due diligence in protecting personal and corporate information.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 18:19:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/14/randomstorm-acquire-dvwa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/14/randomstorm-acquire-dvwa.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Web Application Scanner Poll Results</title>
        
          <description>I started a poll last week on the 1st of December tittled 'Open Source Web Application Vulnerability Scanners'. The aim of this poll was to gain feedback from as many people in the security community as possible to find out which was their preferred open source web application vulnerability scanner, what they preferred about it and what they would improve about their favorite scanner. The poll has run for almost 7 days. The poll link was posted on Twitter (via my Twitter account), on this blog and on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhacker.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.ethicalhacker.net&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

The total number of submissions was 32 however there were some anomalies in the data mainly due to my own fault. I had originally included Burp Suite, I had confused their free version with it being open source, it turns out this is not the case. I also had submissions from application developers, I did not state that I wouldn't be counting their votes however I believe it fairer if we didn't. After taking out the votes for Burp Suite (3 before removing the option), the submissions from application developers (2) and submissions for other commercial scanners (2), it left us with a total of 25 submissions.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 13:38:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/07/open-source-web-application-scanner-poll-results.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/07/open-source-web-application-scanner-poll-results.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Web Application Scanner Poll</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to find out from the community which open source web application scanners they use and why. Please take the poll, once, and answer honestly. Thank you! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?formkey=dFNpQmNfUWx4UEFicW0wQXlZTFQyV0E6MA&quot;&gt;http://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?formkey=dFNpQmNfUWx4UEFicW0wQXlZTFQyV0E6MA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:06:19 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/02/open-source-web-application-scanner-poll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/12/02/open-source-web-application-scanner-poll.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>rfc in your pocket</title>
        
          <description>I wanted to start reading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2616.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RFC 2616 HTTP/1.1&lt;/a&gt;, because who knows more about how HTTP works than the inventors right?! The only problem was, is that I hate reading large documents from screens, I lose concentration after very little time and end up on Twitter or some other social networking site.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

So I started looking for printed RFCs, someone must have put these in a book?! Well, it turns out that I couldn't find any. I thought about printing the entire RFC from my university library (£0.10 a page) however RFC 2616 contains 176 pages (£17.60 total). I remembered that OWASP use lulu.com for printing their awesome books, so I decided to print my own RFC and make it into a book. After many hours of trying to fit the A4 RFC into a pocket-size (4.25&quot; x 6.88&quot;) book, getting the font size right, aligning the page numbers and getting the formatting just right on all 176 pages, 'rfc in your pocket' was ready to upload! After lots of trial and error with reformatting and trying to get the whole thing to fit I decided to order one for myself.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/DSC04535.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-458&quot; title=&quot;DSC04535&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/DSC04535-188x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC04535&quot; width=&quot;188&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 19:00:29 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/22/rfc-in-your-pocket.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/22/rfc-in-your-pocket.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>IE8 XSS Filter bypasses</title>
        
          <description>When Microsoft launched their new Internet Explorer (IE) 8 browser in March of this year, it boasted a new security feature which filtered malicious scripting code to prevent reflected type 1 XSS attacks known as the 'XSS Filter'.

&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

Cesar Cerrudo, while IE8 was still in BETA found a way to bypass the filter by using a '2 stage XSS attack':
&lt;blockquote&gt;A 2 stage XSS attack is when the user has to browse to a second URL after browing the initial URL for the XSS attack to take place, people may think that this attack is compliated and not reliable but it's simple and very realiable and has almost the same success rate as 1 stage XSS attack since people want to get what they were looking when browsing to the first URL they will continue browsing most of the time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 01:03:20 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/20/ie8-xss-filter-bypass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/20/ie8-xss-filter-bypass.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>1 year on</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is exactly one year on after posting my first &lt;a title=&quot;first post&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/2008/11/12/project-camelot-interviews-gary-mckinnon/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on the blog. I had a premature celebration (couldn't hold the excitement) by changing the design as you have all probably noticed. I am still working on he re-design so there may still be some glitches here and there, bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have come a long way since that first post and learnt a great deal. In 12 months I have created and managed DVWA to the success it is now with lots of help from the community. I have done talks, written articles and been a guest on some great podcasts. I completed my first year at university with the grade I set out to achieve and I am now half way through my second year still going strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this I could not have achieved with out my friends, family and the online security community. The infosec community is always there to lend a hand and has opened up great opportunity's for me. If you are an Ethical Hacking student or security professional and your not involved in the community, I cant stress enough how beneficial it is to contribute and learn from the amazing people that our out there. I would like to name names however there's so many of you that have helped me I'm afraid I might miss some one out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With out you the reader there would be no point in me keeping the blog updated with new posts, so please comment, give feedback and let me know what you would like to see more of. Also, don't forget to subscribe! Blue box on the right. ;) --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again a big thank you to you all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 02:33:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/12/1-year-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/12/1-year-on.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Securing your web applications</title>
        
          <description>The World Wide Web and the applications that run on it have come a long way since the invention of HTML by Tim Berners-Lee (British man I might add) in the early 1990’s. Back then the World Wide Web was a static web of text, images and hyperlinks. Nowadays we have the privilege (sometimes not) of having whole communities which solely exist in a dynamically evolving cyberspace with wikis, blogs, social networking, video sharing and a lot more. “Web 2.0” would not exist without the complex web applications that run on the millions of web servers across the globe.

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;So how do we go about securing our web applications?&lt;/strong&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 14:03:25 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/08/securing-your-web-applications.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/11/08/securing-your-web-applications.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Interview] Chris John Riley - 'The Änal Security Guy'</title>
        
          <description>For our second ever interviewee we have Chris John Riley the 'Änal Security Guy'. Chris was born in the UK and is now living in Austria. He has been in the IT industry for over 13 years, he now works as a IT Security Analyst doing penetration testing internally and for external clients.

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How did you get started in information security?&lt;/h4&gt;

Well I've always been interested in security I guess. Although I always used to think of it as an unhealthy interest in how things really worked under the hood. I've broken my fair share of systems be being too curious what would happen if I just changed or deleted this or that file. Then again, who hasn't done that once in a while.

I guess the real turning point was while I was working in Munich, Germany. An interesting project came across my desk that really seemed interesting to me. The project was a simple one, install and configure an Intrusion Detection System to protect an external server farm, and schedule regular vulnerability scans. But to tell you the truth, the project wasn't really what made me want to do security, it was the response from the management after the project was finished. I sat down with one of the bosses and started to go through one of the vulnerability reports I'd run. Lots of red and yellow alerts, and things to change. His response, was that the IDS and scans where simply a contract requirement to win a customer bid, and nobody had the time or interest in changing things. We'd ticked the box that said we have IDS and run regular scans, project done, please move on.

As you can imagine this didn't sit too well, but there wasn't much I could do at the time. I was still learning German and could rock the boat. So, moving on I tried to work security into the next couple of projects and found it increasingly hard to get the point across that security should be built in at the ground level and not just ignored. Well to cut a long story short, I asked for 4 weeks leave to attend some training (self funded naturally) and it was turned down. At that point I decided I'd be better off moving on and finding a position that supported security and didn't punish it. So I handed in my notice, did my training and made the move to Austria to be with my girlfriend.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 12:51:25 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/20/interview-chris-john-riley-the-anal-security-guy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/20/interview-chris-john-riley-the-anal-security-guy.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[BONSAI] XSS and SQL Injection in Achievo &lt;= 1.3.4</title>
        
          <description>Today Andres Riancho owner of &lt;a title=&quot;BONSAI&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bonsai-sec.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bonsai Information Security&lt;/a&gt; (Argentina) and lead developer of &lt;a title=&quot;W3AF&quot; href=&quot;http://w3af.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;w3af&lt;/a&gt; has released a couple of advisories on vulnerabilities in &lt;a title=&quot;Achievo&quot; href=&quot;http://www.achievo.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Achievo&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;= 1.3.4 which we found a few months ago after our vulnerability research into common web applications.

The affected web application is Achievo &amp;lt;= 1.3.4. Achievo suffered from multiple simple persistent XSS vulnerabilities within their scheduler module and an SQL injection vulnerability within their dispatch.php file.

Achievo is a flexible web-based resource management tool for business environments. Achievo's resource management capabilities will enable organisations to support their business processes in a simple, but effective manner.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 14:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/17/bonsai-xss-and-sql-injection-in-achievo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/17/bonsai-xss-and-sql-injection-in-achievo.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Netsparker - The next gen web app scanner</title>
        
          <description>&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-328&quot; title=&quot;netsparker-logo-splash&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/netsparker-logo-splash.png&quot; alt=&quot;netsparker-logo-splash&quot; width=&quot;334&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; /&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

I was lucky enough to get my greasy hands on a copy of &lt;em&gt;'Netsparker Final BETA'&lt;/em&gt; from Mavituna Security's project leader Ferruh Mavituna.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Netsparker can crawl, attack and identify vulnerabilities in all custom web applications regardless of the platform and the technology it's built on, just like an actual attacker. It can identify web application vulnerabilities like SQL Injection, Cross-site Scripting (XSS), Remote Code Execution and many more.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

I tested Netsparker v0.9.9.9935 (FINAL BETA) against DVWA v1.0.6. Setting up a new scan was as easy as putting in the DVWA URL, adding the security/PHPSESSID cookies and then selecting the different vulnerabilities to scan for. Netsparker picked up on almost all of DVWA's vulnerabilities, even the SQL Injection vulnerability which a lot of web application scanners have problems picking up for some reason. The vulnerabilities that it did not pick up on I sent in an email to Ferruh, he has already added scans for some of these and will implement others in future.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 13:22:54 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/11/netsparker-the-next-gen-web-app-scanner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/11/netsparker-the-next-gen-web-app-scanner.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[Interview] Rob Loos - 'Students in Security'</title>
        
          <description>We have decided to start interviewing people in infosec to talk about various security topics. Our first ever interviewee is Rob Loos!

Rob Loos is a Belgium Applied Computer Science student at KHK Geel Belgium University who has a massive interest in the security world and loves to get other students involved too.

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What started you out in information security?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
I've always had an interest in computers, playing games, writing a few small programs and helping other people out. As many security people I enjoyed the forums a lot and got in contact with people who's hat were pretty far from white. I got a lot of blackhat knowledge that way, even tough most was pretty scriptkiddy. I got experienced with malware, remote administration and some webapp exploiting. Its a lot of fun but not something that can get you a good future.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 14:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/06/interview-rob-loos-students-in-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/10/06/interview-rob-loos-students-in-security.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Defcon too far? Blackhat too expensive? No problem!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Have no fear SecurityTubeCon is here! (well... soon!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SecurityTubeCon is the first hacker conference to be held completely in cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;SecurityTubeCon is aimed at democratizing hacker conferences by allowing any researcher, regardless of his physical location, to share his work with the community. Unlike other Cons we will not *accept / reject* speakers. If you have something interesting to share, you WILL be heard. The idea behind SecurityTubeCon is not to pass judgments on your work, instead, it aims at providing a platform for knowledge exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ive always wanted to attend a hacker conference however for a poor student like me its not easy. If you don't live in a big city you have to get to the conference by plane or train (£100 to £500), buy a ticket to attend (£50 to £1000), pay for a hotel (£100 - £300) and then pay for food/beer (£50 - £150), not to mention the time off work. All in all it can be an expensive trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SecurityTubeCon will be held on the 6th, 7th and and 8th of November. Location: cyberspace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on SecurityTubeCon or if your interested in giving a talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://securitytubecon.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://securitytubecon.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 18:08:20 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/09/12/defcon-too-far-blackhat-too-expensive-no-problem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/09/12/defcon-too-far-blackhat-too-expensive-no-problem.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DVWA has a new home</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA) now has a new website dedicated to the online community. The website is the new portal for all things DVWA, from it we plan to expand our online community and take DVWA that one step further.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For the latest news on DVWA, forums, blog posts, code submissions, feedback and everything else DVWA:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a title=&quot;DVWA&quot; href=&quot;http://www.dvwa.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.dvwa.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While your there why not sign up to the forums and say hello! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 20:40:43 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/09/01/dvwa-has-a-new-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/09/01/dvwa-has-a-new-home.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DVWA v1.0.5 coming soon...</title>
        
          <description>DVWA v1.0.5 will be released in the near future sporting many changes including more vulnerabilities and features.

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

Since version 1.0.4 we have a bigger open source community which have pushed DVWA to a whole new level, with out them the project couldn't be what it is today.

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;DVWA v1.0.5 change log:&lt;/strong&gt;

Complete re-code.

Complete re-design.

CSRF vulnerability.

Stored XSS vulnerability.

Full Path Disclosure vulnerability.

Login page.

Sessions.

Many bug fixes.

PHPIDS implementation.

+ much more

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 18:50:15 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/08/23/dvwa-v1-0-5-coming-soon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/08/23/dvwa-v1-0-5-coming-soon.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>[BONSAI] SQL Injection in CS-Cart &lt;= 2.0.5</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the vulnerabilities which I found during my research for &lt;a title=&quot;Bonsai Security&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bonsai-sec.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bonsai Security&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. The research consisted of vulnerability assessing commercial and open source ecommerce web applications over a 2 week period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time of my research I learnt a great deal from Andres Riancho (&lt;a title=&quot;w3af&quot; href=&quot;http://w3af.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;w3af&lt;/a&gt;/bonsai-sec owner) and from the vulnerability assessments them selves. So what did I learn? I learnt that patience is definitely a virtue, javascript is a pain in the ass, ecommerce web application developers need to invest more time on security and a lot more as regards to perfecting my assessment techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the vulnerability report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;cs-cart_SQL-injection-0100&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bonsai-sec.com/research/vulnerabilities/cs-cart_SQL-injection-0100.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.bonsai-sec.com/research/vulnerabilities/cs-cart_SQL-injection-0100.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a great post by Andres on the difficulty on the actual exploitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;not-the-average-sql-injection&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bonsai-sec.com/blog/index.php/not-the-average-sql-injection/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.bonsai-sec.com/blog/index.php/not-the-average-sql-injection/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A massive thanks to Andres for giving me the opportunity to work for him. I learnt more in the (just over) two week period working for him than I could have learnt in a whole 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:49:02 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/08/05/bonsai-sql-injection-in-cs-cart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/08/05/bonsai-sql-injection-in-cs-cart.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Pentest Labs: Web Application Edition (securityaegis)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to set up a complete web application penetration testing lab with all the best tools available? Here is an awesome video by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securityaegis.com&quot;&gt;www.securityaegis.com&lt;/a&gt; to show you how to do it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;object classid=&quot;clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;src&quot; value=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5729732&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5729732&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/5729732&quot;&gt;Web App Lab Setup&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/laz3r&quot;&gt;Laz3r (of Securityaegis.com)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For a full write up on how to do this or for more information check out their original blog post:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securityaegis.com/?p=574&quot;&gt;http://www.securityaegis.com/?p=574&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 12:27:03 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/07/28/pentest-labs-web-application-edition-securityaegis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/07/28/pentest-labs-web-application-edition-securityaegis.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>dvwa video presentation at SuperMondays</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the video from my presentation on dvwa at the &lt;a title=&quot;supermondays&quot; href=&quot;http://www.supermondays.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SuperMondays&lt;/a&gt; event in Newcastle Upon Tyne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;object id=&quot;viddler_b9c7c6d1&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000&quot; width=&quot;437&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;src&quot; value=&quot;http://www.viddler.com/simple/b9c7c6d1/&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;name&quot; value=&quot;viddler_b9c7c6d1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed id=&quot;viddler_b9c7c6d1&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;437&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; src=&quot;http://www.viddler.com/simple/b9c7c6d1/&quot; name=&quot;viddler_b9c7c6d1&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I must hold the record for the amount of &quot;ammm...&quot; 's in a 16 minute period! My first public talk so much room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 12:17:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/07/03/dvwa-video-presentation-at-supermondays.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/07/03/dvwa-video-presentation-at-supermondays.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>dvwa v1.0.4 released</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;After a month of coding Damn Vulnerable Web App (dvwa) v1.0.4 is ready for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dvwa v1.0.4 has many changes from the 1.0.3 version. Mostly bug fixes and better design changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.0.4 Change log:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added acunetix scan report. 24/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
All links use http://hiderefer.com to hide referrer header. 23/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Updated/added 'more info' links. 23/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Moved change log info to CHANGELOG.txt. 22/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed the exec.php UTF-8 output. 16/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Moved Help/View source buttons to footer. 12/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed phpInfo bug. 12/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Made dvwa IE friendly. 11/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed html bugs. 11/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Added more info to about page. 03/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Added pictures for the users. 03/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Fixed typos on the welcome page. 03/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Improved README.txt and fixed typos. 03/06/2009&lt;br /&gt;
Made SQL injection possible in sqli_med.php. Thanks to Teodor Lupan. 03/06/2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any suggestions/feedback/contributions welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download: &lt;a title=&quot;dvwa&quot; href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/dvwa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/dvwa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 17:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/06/29/dvwa-v1-0-4-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/06/29/dvwa-v1-0-4-released.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>w3af</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ive just finished coding a wordpress version fingerprinting plugin for w3af so I thought id let you all know what w3af is and how you can contribute too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;w3af is a Web Application Attack and Audit Framework. The project's goal is to create a framework to find and exploit web application vulnerabilities that is easy to use and extend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Any serious security professional should have w3af in their tool kit, w3af can discover, evade, audit and exploit web application vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin I developed (wordpress_fingerprint) scans wordpress installations for their version. It does this by first checking that wordpress is installed, if it is it will check to see if the version is in the index header source code and will then go through a list of fingerprinting data. The plugin will find the version even if there is a security plugin installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contribute to w3af:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mailing list: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/mail/?group_id=170274&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/mail/?group_id=170274&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRC channel: &lt;a href=&quot;irc://irc.freenode.net:8001/w3af&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;irc://irc.freenode.net:8001/w3af&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/w3af/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/w3af/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to Andres Riancho for a great tool and for helping me develop the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 16:48:13 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/06/08/w3af.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/06/08/w3af.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DVWA NEEDS YOU!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;That's right, &lt;strong&gt;YOU!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn Vulnerable Web App is an open source project and in order for it to be successful we need your contributions. So far dvwa has been solely developed by me with some help from a couple of friends, I my self cannot make the project as successful as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need contributions of any kind, suggestions, design, marketing, coding, ect...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What benefits are their to contributing to an open source project?&lt;/strong&gt; Lots! It enables you to enhance your skills/knowledge, it looks good on your CV, it gets your name/website around, it shows future employers that your dedicated to enhancing the security industry and much more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;2009-06-22T12:52:57+00:00&quot;&gt;Make the CSS cross platform.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve the current vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop more vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improve the design/look/feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;2009-07-17T23:39:51+00:00&quot;&gt;Design a logo.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;2009-07-17T23:39:51+00:00&quot;&gt;Improve the code.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the word out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to contribute:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can contribute by leaving messages on this blog or by emailing &lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-210&quot; title=&quot;dvwa_email&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/05/dvwa_email.png&quot; alt=&quot;dvwa_email&quot; width=&quot;190&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;.  All code/content contributors can have their name/link on the about page in dvwa (if they wish).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 01:48:29 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/30/dvwa-needs-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/30/dvwa-needs-you.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Damn Vulnerable Web App installation video</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a video on installing and running dvwa, this is my first video so if I sound nervous its because I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object classid=&quot;clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;src&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/GzIj07jt8rM&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/GzIj07jt8rM&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&amp;lt;/embed&amp;gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments welcome, good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 18:54:49 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/25/damn-vulnerable-web-app-installation-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/25/damn-vulnerable-web-app-installation-video.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Damn Vulnerable Web App v.1</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Damn Vulnerable Web App v.1 has been released!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now easier to install than ever, its more realistic and it even has a help button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made command execution more realistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added help buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added .htaccess file to turn magic quotes off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved database creation with setup.php.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amended installation instructions in README file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added GNU GPL license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added a robots.txt file with disallow all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removed link to www.ethicalhacker.co.uk in footer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added better error output on magic quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DVWA is now open source and we are looking for contributors! Lets make it the number one choice when teaching/learning hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stuff that needs doing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More realism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DVWA v.1 is now available on SourceForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;DVWA v.1 &quot; href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/dvwa/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOWNLOAD DVWA v.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 21:04:02 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/20/damn-vulnerable-web-app-v1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/05/20/damn-vulnerable-web-app-v1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Guest post: Current Available UK Degrees</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the UK there is, that I have been able to find only three universities offering a variation of Ethical Hacking Degrees;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; &lt;a title=&quot;Northumbria Ethical Hacking&quot; href=&quot;http://northumbria.ac.uk/?view=CourseDetail&amp;amp;code=UUSETH1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethical Hacking for Computer Security - Northumbria University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; &lt;a title=&quot;Coventry Ethical Hacking&quot; href=&quot;http://wwwm.coventry.ac.uk/undergraduate/ugstudy/Pages/ugft.aspx?itemID=293&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethical Hacking and Network Security - Coventry University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; &lt;a title=&quot;Ethical Hacking Aberdeen&quot; href=&quot;http://www.abertay.ac.uk/Courses/CDetails.cfm?CID=363&amp;amp;Key=004.002&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethical Hacking and Countermeasures - University of Abertay Dundee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the course at Northumbria was in the development stages there was even media attention drawn to it, as the name before it's change was simply &quot;Ethical Hacking&quot; although I could not fins the story surrounding it's name &lt;a class=&quot;postlink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/tyne/content/articles/2008/02/06/ethical_hacking_feature.shtml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a link to a story on the subject itself. Funnily enough there is also a blog post on it although not many replies it shows how much attention the thought of people learning to hack has brought about. &lt;a class=&quot;postlink&quot; href=&quot;http://slipouts.blogspot.com/2008/09/ethical-hacking-degree-certified.html&quot;&gt;Blog Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ffffff;&quot;&gt;'&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Regardless of the attention that the subject receives there is still a great demand for security professionals within many industries, I was at a Business risk management conference, at the end of this month and as was quite surprised at the lack of knowledge business people had in regards to what data could be found on the internet, and how insecure any server can be if not maintained and configured correctly. Ethical Hackers are needed not only to Information Gather--&amp;gt;Carry out vulnerability tests--&amp;gt;and Penetration testing but also to educate people and companies. The degrees provided in the UK are a great way for Ethical Hackers to start off and be recognised to have the knowledge to do this, along with other certifications available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this information is useful to people looking into university courses at the moment, please feel free to ask any questions regarding the Northumbria course as I am currently on it .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1337speak&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 16:32:55 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/04/29/guest-post-current-available-uk-degrees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/04/29/guest-post-current-available-uk-degrees.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ScreenStamp!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We are glad to finally be able to let you all know that ScreenStamp! is nearly ready for release and that we are looking for BETA testers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is ScreenStamp!?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ScreenStamp! is a project that I, 1337speak and cpbx have been working on for the past couple of months. Its aim is to be a fully automated screenshot application that will be available for Windows, Linux and eventually Mac's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another screenshot application??? Aren't there enough out there??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are lots of screenshot applications out there, however there is none that we could find that did exactly what we wanted. The idea came to us when recently undergoing a information gathering and vulnerability assessment, we had to capture screenshots of all the information that we had gathered in order to represent it as evidence. Every one in the group of 5 had at least 50 screenshots each, which all had to be captured, saved to an image editing application, date/timed, named and then saved to a file location on the hard drive. This proved to take a very long time when taking lots of screenshots!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does ScreenStamp! do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been designed to be as fully automated as possible, non intrusive, easy to use/install and free. Here are some of the features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takes a screenshot from the PrtSc button on the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puts date/time onto the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Names and saves the image to a preset location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can I download it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ScreenStamp! Linux and Win are almost finished, we are now looking for BETA testers to find bugs and recommend improvements. If you are interested in being a BETA tester, please email development&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;screenstamp.co.uk and indicate which version you would like to test, Linux, WIndows or both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ffffff;&quot;&gt;'&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other info:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ScreenStamp! Win will be released as freeware and ScreenStamp! Linux as open source under the GNU General Public License. ScreenStamp! Win was developed in C# while ScreenStamp! Linux was developed in Python 2.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;http://www.screenstamp.co.uk&quot; href=&quot;http://www.screenstamp.co.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.screenstamp.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 22:05:53 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/04/03/screenstamp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/04/03/screenstamp.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Blog updates</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just to let everyone know that we are now running the latest version of wordpress, finally! If you haven't noticed already there's a 'Security Jobs' RSS feed which grabs RSS feeds off a number of job sites, the link can be found in the sidebar above the google ads.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ive fixed the footer as it was out of line and also made the pagination a little bit nicer however during the process of updating the site I seem to have messed up the 'pages', the ones in the green bar at the top. Haven't a clue whats gone wrong, spent the past few hours staring at CSS, PHP and HTML and still cannot figure out what I have done!!! I'm going to leave it for now and come back to it another day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some exiting news...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and some other lads from university have started a project called 'ScreenStamp!' I will be posting about it shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 15:57:24 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/30/blog-updates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/30/blog-updates.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Using a web bug for information gathering</title>
        
          <description>Abstract:
Any one can post an image anywhere that allows the posting of remote images, grab the http header information of any one who views the image and save it to a log file on a remote server. This has been done for a while by the advertisement industry to track users activities. It can also be used by mail clients to check that an email has been read by the recipient. It is known as a 'web bug'.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 17:55:07 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/15/using-a-web-bug-for-information-gathering.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/15/using-a-web-bug-for-information-gathering.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>General update</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just to let everyone know that I'm still alive. Haven't posted in nearly a month! Been busy with university and also had a couple of jobs on the side.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Damn Vulnerable Web App got a mention on irongeek.com this month! Thanks irongeek!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irongeek.com/i.php?page=security/deliberately-insecure-web-applications-for-learning-web-app-security&quot;&gt;Deliberately Insecure Web Applications For Learning Web App Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I will be posting about my views regarding BBC Click Online hacking into botnets, using them to carry out tests and then changing the computers wallpapers to make the users aware that they were zombies. Is that legal? I will be posting about this over the next few days.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mean while check out the video: &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/programmes/click_online/7932816.stm&quot;&gt;BBC team exposes cyber crime risk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 16:20:55 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/13/general-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/03/13/general-update.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Webserverwatcher.py</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;During our last information gathering and vulnerability assessment project our team realised that the IP address and web server software had changed from when we initially started out. Some time during the project the IT department had changed servers, which meant that some of our data from before the change was now obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some one on our team came up with an idea for a program that would monitor the server for any changes and notify us when it had happened. We would then know as soon as possible and could document this in our final report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following Python code checks the web server every hour for changes in IP address, HTTP server header and x-powered-by header. If it notices any change it logs it to a log file aptly named log.txt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/webserverwatcher.py&quot;&gt;webserverwatcher.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any feedback welcomed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2009 02:25:16 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/15/webserverwatcherpy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/15/webserverwatcherpy.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BackTrack 4 Beta Public Released </title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Weve gone live with the beta, and the downloads are going crazy. All our mirrors are at 90 mbit, more or less.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the iso here md5sum and sha512sum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the VMWare image here md5sum and sha512sum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are trying to get estimates of downloads. If you link to our ISOs, please use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.remote-exploit.org/cgi-bin/fileget?version=bt4-beta-iso&lt;br /&gt;
http://www.remote-exploit.org/cgi-bin/fileget?version=bt4-beta-vm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and do not link them directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Release information will shortly be available on the Remote Exploit Web site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cant seem to find a change-log as yet, I think it has only been released in the past few hours. It was pre-released at Shmoocon 2009 a couple of weeks ago. I haven't downloaded and tested BT4 however I will definitely be taking a look once I have some spare time. Download it and let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 02:30:59 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/11/backtrack-4-beta-public-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/11/backtrack-4-beta-public-released.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My new Acer Aspire One</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just bought an Acer Aspire One! It cost me £150 from ASDA (instore only), here are the specs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OS: Linpus Lite (Linux)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAM: 512MB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HDD: IDE 1.8&quot; 160GB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processor: Intel Atom N270  											1.6 GHz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display: 8.9&quot; 1024x600&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/acer-aspire-one-mini-laptop.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-146&quot; title=&quot;acer-aspire-one-mini-laptop&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/acer-aspire-one-mini-laptop-300x257.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is not too small, it has a normal sized UK enter button, screen size is fine and its very light. You can buy a 1GB RAM stick that only costs £10 from crucial however to fit it you have to pull the whole machine apart. Why didnt they just install a flap at the base of the machine for easy access? God knows! I havent upgraded the RAM yet however I am considering it. The default user interface is designed for babies however migrating to the 'advanced' mode and the XFCE desktop was only a few clicks away. Linpus Lite comes with the XFCE desktop enviroment which I think is fine, I may change to another Linux distro in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some links that I found usefull as a AA1 owner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;www.aspireoneuser.com&quot; href=&quot;http://www.aspireoneuser.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.aspireoneuser.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;linuxhaxor &quot; href=&quot;http://www.linuxhaxor.net/2008/09/27/30-cool-acer-aspire-one-hacks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.linuxhaxor.net/2008/09/27/30-cool-acer-aspire-one-hacks/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 20:50:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/01/my-new-acer-aspire-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/02/01/my-new-acer-aspire-one.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hacking DECT</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite an old story dating back to December 2008, some how I must have missed it. DECT (Digital Enhanced Cordless Telecommunications) is a standard used for cordless/wireless telephones widely used in homes and businesses across the world. (UK frequency: 1880 MHz–1900 MHz)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A project know as deDECTed.org run by a group of German university students has managed to circumvent DECT's security implementations. Not by cracking the secret DECT Standard Authentication Algorithm (DSAA) but instead they realised that sometimes DECT phones used no encryption or authentication at all when communicating with their base station&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When no encryption is used by a DECT phone the researchers found that with a modified 23euro PCMCIA DECT wireless card they could capture and record all audio data passively using their custom built Linux drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a DECT phone at home as I'm sure most people now a days do. It's quite a scary thought to think that with enough technical knowledge any one can listen to your telephone conversations remotely and passively. I'm sure they would be nothing interesting to be heard on my phone, apart from the occasional take away order, however occasionally I do contact my ISP or bank and provide them with my authentication details to access my accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information: &lt;a title=&quot;dedected.org&quot; href=&quot;https://dedected.org/trac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://dedected.org/trac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources: &lt;a title=&quot;the register&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2008/12/31/dect_hack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2008/12/31/dect_hack/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;dedected pdf&quot; href=&quot;https://dedected.org/trac/raw-attachment/wiki/25C3/talk-25c3.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://dedected.org/trac/raw-attachment/wiki/25C3/talk-25c3.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 03:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/01/23/hacking-dect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/01/23/hacking-dect.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cyber warfare on Hamas</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The war between Israel and Hamas has spilled out onto the Internet. This is no surprise as cyber warfare has been going on for years. The Chinese launched the 'Code Red' worm when an American spy plane collided with one of their fighter jets in 2001 infecting 359,000 hosts in a bid to carry out DDoS attacks on high profile American computers including the white house. Georgia's government websites were the victim of Russian hackers back in August 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website set up by a group of Israeli students is actively encouraging users to install software similar to that used by SETI to distribute its data to be processed by idle computers. The website &lt;a title=&quot;www.help-israel-win.org&quot; href=&quot;http://www.help-israel-win.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://66.102.9.104/translate_c?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=iw&amp;amp;u=http://www.help-israel-win.org/&amp;amp;prev=/search%3Fq%3Dhttp://www.help-israel-win.org/%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DG&amp;amp;usg=ALkJrhgtJO8m56udgWv52UhO60tGZxJkzQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.help-israel-win.org&lt;/a&gt; is using the same software and technology to use thousands of computer's bandwidth to DDoS Hamas and Hamas supporting websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From their website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are a group of students who are tired of sitting around doing nothing while the citizens of Sderot and the cities around the Gazza Strip are suffering, NO MORE!&lt;br /&gt;
We will not sit around and watch our children fear and cry out for help while the missiles are flying over their heads!&lt;br /&gt;
We say NO MORE!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this post they claim to have &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small; font-family: tahoma; color: black;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8039&lt;/strong&gt; people that have joined them so far. &lt;/span&gt;(not sure if this means downloading the software or actually registering and allowing the software to use their computers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand there are also lots of hackers attacking Israeli websites and networks, this can be seen through out the black hat community forums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;themoscowtimes&quot; href=&quot;http://www.themoscowtimes.com/article/1009/42/369722.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.themoscowtimes.com/article/1009/42/369722.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;inn.co.il&quot; href=&quot;http://74.125.77.132/search?q=cache:uO-8nu2Bj1wJ:www.inn.co.il/News/News.aspx/183688+http://www.help-israel-win.org/&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ct=clnk&amp;amp;cd=10&amp;amp;gl=uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.inn.co.il/News/News.aspx/183688&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 17:34:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/01/06/cyber-warfare-on-hamas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2009/01/06/cyber-warfare-on-hamas.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Damn Vulnerable Web App BETA is here!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA) is a web application that is damn vulnerable. Its main goals are to be light weight, easy to use and full of vulnerabilities to exploit. It has been developed for the use of information security professionals and students to test out their skillz and/or toolz in a legal environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;WARNING!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn Vulnerable Web App is damn vulnerable! So don't upload it to your hosting provider's public html folder or have it up on any working web site as it will be hacked. I recommend downloading and installing Apache, PHP and MySQL onto a local computer inside your LAN which is used solely for testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not take responsibility for the way in which any one uses this application. I have made the purposes of the application clear and it should not be used maliciously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ffffff;&quot;&gt;'&lt;br /&gt;
'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version: BETA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download DVWA &lt;a title=&quot;DVWA BETA&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/DVWA_BETA.zip&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's still in BETA version so I'm open to suggestions and criticism, if you download and use it please leave some feedback good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://img242.imageshack.us/img242/4171/screenshotjz4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;DVWA BETA&quot; src=&quot;http://img242.imageshack.us/img242/4171/screenshotjz4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;216&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 01:26:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/17/damn-vulnerable-web-app-beta-is-here.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/17/damn-vulnerable-web-app-beta-is-here.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Gary McKinnon's final day in court</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Gary McKinnon's final court date has been pushed back to the 20th January 2009 (the same day Obama takes office).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors say he shut down thousands of machines and caused up to $700,000 worth of damage, while the 42-year-old claims he was searching for evidence of UFOs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the case, defence lawyers argued that McKinnon will face unduly harsh punishment for his actions and should instead face trial in the UK, since the alleged hacking attacks were conducted from a house in north London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time the decision is made, it will be almost seven years since McKinnon ended his activities. During that time a succession of arguments have been made against his removal – including that he faces up to 60 years in prison or detention at Guantánamo Bay, and that he should receive leniency because he suffers from Asperger's syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start from the top, &quot;$700,000 worth of damage&quot;. As far as I'm aware the American government have not produced any evidence to support the amount of damage caused. From what I've read so far Gary broke the Computer Misuse Act 1990 (c.18) point 1, &quot;Unauthorised access to computer material&quot; by logging in to American government, Army, NASA and other American institutions by using a windows null administrator password scanner. He may have broke point 2 of the CMA, &quot;Unauthorised access with intent to commit or facilitate commission of further offences&quot; by using the administrator account to gain further access to other machines or services on the networks. He may also have broke point 3 &quot;Unauthorised modification of computer material&quot;, however I'm not aware of the full details. You could argue that he broke point 3 by viewing some of NASA's pictures, as by doing this he was changing the metadata unknowingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He broke the Computer Misuse Act on British soil. In my opinion he should be punished in Britain. Ive heard about a new European cyber crime bill being discussed at the moment regarding liability, in short it means that if you leave your network wide open for attack then you are partly liable. However as far as I'm aware this is still being discussed and wouldn't affect Gary's case anyway as it wasn't about when he committed his crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its been 7 years since his crimes were committed and he still hasn't been sentenced. I bet he just wants to get it over and done with by now. If the British government didn't see a problem with extraditing him then why is the process taking so long? There must be some disagreement at a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now we will just have to wait and see what happens on the 20th of Jan and hope that he wins his case to serve his sentence in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also a demonstration outside the American embassy in London on Friday the 5th of December 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a title=&quot;gardian gary mckinnon&quot; href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2008/dec/02/mckinnon-extradition-hacker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info: &lt;a title=&quot;free gary &quot; href=&quot;http://freegary.org.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;freegary.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 21:57:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/03/gary-mckinnons-final-day-in-court.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/03/gary-mckinnons-final-day-in-court.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Iran executes IT expert who spied for Israel</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;A COMPUTER expert has been executed in Iran after he confessed to working for Mossad, the Israeli intelligence service. This provides a rare insight into the intense espionage activity inside the Islamic republic.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
He was obviously playing a dangerous game and paid for it with his life.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ali Ashtari, 43, a computer and hi-tech equipment buyer for Iran’s defence industry and nuclear programme, was hanged after admitting he worked for Israel. It is the first known conviction of an alleged Israeli agent in Iran for almost 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashtari was trusted by senior officials to travel overseas to buy the advanced computers and other electronic equipment needed for the regime’s nuclear programme, which is reported to have already produced enough enriched uranium to make an atomic bomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind their backs he allowed the software he bought to be subtly doctored by Israeli computer engineers before it was imported to Iran. Ashtari confessed: “Mossad’s goal was to sell specialised computer equipment through me to Iranian intelligence organisations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You would have thought that Iran would have been more careful as to who they employ and how trustworthy they are. Who knows how many backdoors are still open within Iran's nuclear facility?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full story &lt;a title=&quot;Times online iran execution&quot; href=&quot;http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/news/world/middle_east/article5258057.ece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/01/iran-executes-it-expert-who-spied-for-israel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/12/01/iran-executes-it-expert-who-spied-for-israel.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DEFCON London - Christmas meeting</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;DEFCON London - Christmas meeting - Tuesday 2nd December 2008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, folks, it's that time of the year/month again...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be our last meeting of 2008, so we're planning to make it a&lt;br /&gt;
goodun!!! All are welcome, but remember - Fight Club rules apply... If&lt;br /&gt;
this is your first meet, you *will* talk... :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If your planning on going for the first time be prepared to talk!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time we've got:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Bluetooth fun &amp;amp; Wargames - Christer &amp;amp; Mr K (long talk, double slot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- 'hacking rogue for fun &amp;amp; profit (mostly profit)' - freakyclown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Coring BlueCore - Mark&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Its a shame that Christmas has zapped all my cash. :-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info click &lt;a title=&quot;DEFCON London&quot; href=&quot;http://dc4420.org &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location : &lt;a title=&quot;Glassblower Picadilly&quot; href=&quot;http://www.beerintheevening.com/pubs/s/20/2081/Glassblower/Piccadilly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glassblower&lt;/a&gt;, Piccadilly&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 15:05:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/29/defcon-london-christmas-meeting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/29/defcon-london-christmas-meeting.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Metaspoit's meterpreter</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Meterpreter is a Metasploit payload designed for post-exploitation tasks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the steps involved in completely automating exploitation is post-exploitation automation. This is where steps are taken to automate the tasks that are performed after successfully exploiting a target host. The meterpreter implementation in Metasploit 3.0 defines a programmatic interface for the attacker that helps to facilitate this automation, such as by making it easy to interact with processes, networking, and the file system. While all of this has been present for some time, we have only recently added support for Meterpreter scripts. The purpose of meterpreter scripts are to give end-users an easy interface to write quick scripts that can be run against remote targets after successful exploitation. In the long term, we'll make it so that these scripts can run automatically each time a Meterpreter session is created, thus making the post-exploitation process completely automated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After playing around with it for a few hours Ive realised that its a very powerful tool for any pen tester to have. I tried in vain to record the exploitation and post exploitation process using the open source screen recorder 'CamStudio' however I was unsuccessfully due to it not recording some of the screen. I will try and find alternative software or have another go with CamStudio in the near future to show you all how powerful the meterpreter payload really is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meterpreter has been around since Metasploit version 3 however in the newest version of Metasploit it seems that the meterpreter DLL that gets uploaded to the target machine is no longer detected by anti virus software. In theory Metasploit could scan random IP ranges, exploit targets using autopwn, grab the administrator hashes and then email them to the attacker. A script kiddies wet dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info on meterpreter &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.metasploit.com/2006/10/meterpreter-scripts-and-msrt.html&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view a video of meterpreter in action &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irongeek.com/i.php?page=videos/bypassing-anti-virus-with-metasploit&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 17:38:29 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/27/metaspoits-meterpreter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/27/metaspoits-meterpreter.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Hacking at College</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While looking through some old DEFCON material I came across Sam Bowne's video presentation on teaching hacking at college. The presentation was at DEFCON 15 on August 3-5 2007. He speaks about the practicalities of teaching hacking in an academic fashion. Its a must view if your thinking of taking a career path within the security industry and thinking of starting a course in hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video can be downloaded from &lt;a title=&quot;Teaching Hacking at College video&quot; href=&quot;http://media.defcon.org/dc-15/video/Defcon15-Sam_Bowne-Teaching_Hacking_at_College.mp4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view the full DEFCON archives click &lt;a title=&quot;defcon archives&quot; href=&quot;http://www.defcon.org/html/links/defcon-media-archives.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visit Sam Bowne's personal web site click &lt;a title=&quot;sams class&quot; href=&quot;http://samsclass.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 16:42:17 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/23/teaching-hacking-at-college.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/23/teaching-hacking-at-college.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Live Aid style concert planned to support hacker</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Progressive rock legends Marillion are set to perform at a benefit concert for hacker Gary McKinnon.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;p&gt;A concert is being organised to support the hacker, who the US is currently trying to extradite over charges that he caused $700,000 worth of damage when he allegedly hacked into US security systems at NASA and the Pentagon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be an excellent way to raise awareness of Gary's case and hopefully encourage a debate regarding the UK/US extradition treaty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Hemsworth, who is also UK director of the International UFO Congress, plans to organise a ‘Band Aid style' song recorded at Abbey Road studios and hopes George Michael will sing Mr McKinnon's own single, Only a Fool. All proceeds from the concert will go to the Autism Research Centre in Cambridge, after Mr McKinnon was diagnosed with Asperger's syndrome in August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much the tickets would be and what the turn out would be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read the full story &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scmagazineuk.com/Live-Aid-style-concert-planned-to-support-hacker/article/121352/&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see Gary McKinnon's Only a Fool single video &lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=VXHXM-82Wlc&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 13:17:20 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/22/live-aid-style-concert-planned-to-support-hacker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/22/live-aid-style-concert-planned-to-support-hacker.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Steve Wozniak loves iPhone hacks!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The co founder of Apple Inc is seen in an interview with BBC Click's Spencer Kelly admitting he loves hackers. Steve Wozniak is responsible for designing and creating the Apple I and Apple II. In the video clip 'The Woz' chats about the start of Apple Inc and how he set out to change the world of computing. He says he loves iPhone hacks and the fact you can unlock them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/apple_1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-78&quot; title=&quot;Apple 1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/apple_1-150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To see the online BBC Click video &lt;a title=&quot;BBC Click Steve Wozniak&quot; href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/programmes/click_online/7741472.stm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. (5.44 seconds)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 19:27:47 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/21/steve-wozniak-loves-hackers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/21/steve-wozniak-loves-hackers.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Metasploit Framework 3.2 Released</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The new Metasploit Framework was released on the 19th November (yesterday). It has a massive change log with lots of tweaks and add ons. I will try and list the interesting ones here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Version 3.2 includes exploit modules for recent Microsoft flaws, such&lt;br /&gt;
as MS08-041, MS08-053, MS08-059, MS08-067, MS08-068, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I may have to test my Windows 2000 box again and see if any of the above work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Windows payload stagers have been updated to support targets with&lt;br /&gt;
NX CPU support. These stagers now allocate a read/write/exec segment of&lt;br /&gt;
memory for all payload downloads and execution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staggered payloads are the only ones I could get working against Windows 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This release includes a set of man-in-the-middle, authentication relay,&lt;br /&gt;
and authentication capture modules. These modules can be integrated with&lt;br /&gt;
a fake proxy (WPAD), a malicious access point (Karmetasploit), or basic&lt;br /&gt;
network traffic interception to gain access to client machines. These&lt;br /&gt;
modules tie together browser_autopwn, SMB relaying, and HTTP credential&lt;br /&gt;
and form capturing to pillage data from client systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metasploit can now sniff traffic too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Egypt's new PHP payloads provide complete bind, reverse, and findsock&lt;br /&gt;
support for PHP web application exploits. If you are sick of C99 and R57&lt;br /&gt;
and looking to gain a &quot;real&quot; shell from one of the hundreds of RFI flaws&lt;br /&gt;
listed on milw0rm, the new PHP payloads work great against multiple&lt;br /&gt;
operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will have to have play with this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The db_autopwn command has been revamped to support port-based limits,&lt;br /&gt;
regex-based module matching, and limits on the number of spawned jobs. The&lt;br /&gt;
end result is a way to quickly launch specific modules against a specific&lt;br /&gt;
set of target machines. These changes were suggested and implemented by&lt;br /&gt;
Marcell 'SkyOut' Dietl (Helith).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the feature used by Fast|Track, doesn't mention an OS limitation, that would be the next logical step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download Metasploit Framework 3.2 &lt;a title=&quot;metasploit 3.2&quot; href=&quot;http://metasploit.com/framework/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view the full change log &lt;a title=&quot;metasploit 3.2 changelog&quot; href=&quot;http://metasploit.com/documents/RELEASE-3.2.txt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 18:45:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/20/metasploit-framework-32-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/20/metasploit-framework-32-released.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Windows 2000 &amp; Fast|Track</title>
        
          <description>A couple of weeks ago I was going to test Fast|Track against a Windows 98 machine however I couldn't get my wireless card to work on it and I couldn't be arsed moving the PC out of the spare room. I finally got Windows 2000 with no patches or updates up and running. I installed Windows 2000 as according to many its very vulnerable.

Fast|Track is an automated tool that comes pre installed in BackTrack. It scans an ip address or range for open ports using NMap, once it has scanned the machine(s) it trys every exploit for the open ports found using NMap's autopwn feature via Metasploit. It doesn't take any notice of NMap's OS discovery, so even if NMap discovers that the machine is running Windows 2000 with 100% accuracy (it didn't), it will still try other OS exploits.

After Fast|Track had finished scanning and exploiting It gave me 4 active shell sessions that it had spawned from successful exploits.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 19:18:52 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/17/windows-2000-fast-track.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/17/windows-2000-fast-track.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hacking Challenge: Linux Local Kernel Exploit ($5,000)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Armaments October-November Hacking Challenge: 5,000$ Prize - Linux Local Kernel Vulnerabilities and Exploit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I. Details&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Armaments officially announce the launch of October-November hacking challenge.&lt;br /&gt;
The challenge starts on October 1. For the October-November Challenge, Digital Armaments will give a prize of 5,000$ for each submission that results in a Exploitable Vulnerability or Working Exploit for Local Linux Kernel. This should include example and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submission must be sent during the October/November months and be received by midnight EST on November 30, 2008. The 5,000$ PRIZE will be an extra added to the normal vulnerability payment (check the DACP scheme).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it does pay to be hacker! I could buy a whole lot of McDonalds with $5000(~£3400)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info &lt;a title=&quot;hacker challenge&quot; href=&quot;http://www.digitalarmaments.com/content/view/47/27/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 17:34:09 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/14/hacking-challenge-linux-local-kernel-exploit-5000.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/14/hacking-challenge-linux-local-kernel-exploit-5000.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>nUbuntu - for the security aware</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nUbuntu is an Ubuntu live CD with all the desktop packages removed, like gnome, evolution, open office and most other packages which come installed in Ubuntu by default. It comes with many security packages pre installed and ready to use. It could be compared to other security live Cd's like BackTrack or Auditor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where to get it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;nubuntu download&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nubuntu.org/downloads.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.nubuntu.org/downloads.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you install it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the ISO image file, burn it to CD and boot it. What I chose to do was download the ISO image file and make a virtual machine image, so I could run it straight from my desktop as I do with BackTrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a guide on how to create a virtual machine from an ISO image file using VMWare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;creat vmware from iso&quot; href=&quot;http://www.howtoforge.com/create-vmware-machines-from-iso-files-without-burning-cds-dvds&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.howtoforge.com/create-vmware-machines-from-iso-files-without-burning-cds-dvds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I think?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works well, had no problems while booting. I like the fact that all the fancy Ubuntu stuff has been taken out. As for the pre installed scripts and tools (which is what were most interested in), It doesnt have as many tools pre installed as BackTrack does, however it does have some tools which BackTrack doesn't have. A couple of examples would be Wapiti, Nessus and Onesixtyone. It also has an option to install to HDD which BackTrack doesn't have, but the point of a live CD is to boot from the CD, its always nice to have the option tho. I like the fact that BackTrack has FTP, VNC and other server software pre installed, nUbuntu doesnt.  All in all  I think i will be sticking with BackTrack for now, however I will be keeping a close eye on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know! Download it and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info &lt;a title=&quot;nubuntu&quot; href=&quot;http://www.nubuntu.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 18:29:21 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/13/nubuntu-for-the-security-aware.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/13/nubuntu-for-the-security-aware.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>ATM's running Windows 95</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my way to work some time last year when I saw an ATM with a DOS prompt on the screen. So I went over to have a look and took some pics on my mobile phone. The pictures I took revealed that the ATM was running Windows 95. Yes, you read right, Windows 95!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/dsc00098.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-24&quot; title=&quot;dsc00098&quot; src=&quot;http://www.ethicalhack3r.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/dsc00098-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Secunia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 95 has 7 advisories with 3 of them unpatched. (As Microsoft doesn't support Windows 95 anymore they will never be patched.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Solution Status&quot; src=&quot;http://secunia.com/advisories/graph/?type=sol&amp;amp;period=all&amp;amp;prod=393&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;230&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Criticality&quot; src=&quot;http://secunia.com/advisories/graph/?type=cri&amp;amp;period=all&amp;amp;prod=393&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;230&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Where&quot; src=&quot;http://secunia.com/advisories/graph/?type=fro&amp;amp;period=all&amp;amp;prod=393&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;230&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone&quot; title=&quot;Impact&quot; src=&quot;http://secunia.com/advisories/graph/?type=imp&amp;amp;period=all&amp;amp;prod=393&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see Windows 95 is not a very safe OS to run, never mind on an ATM! Lets summarise the graphs above. 50% unpatched, 75% remotely and 50% system access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the question is, how safe is your money? Not very by the looks of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 19:42:27 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/12/atms-running-windows-95.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/12/atms-running-windows-95.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Project Camelot interviews Gary McKinnon</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite an old video, &lt;span id=&quot;duration-and-date&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Nov 9, 2007&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Its interesting to hear Gary's defence straight from the horses mouth. At first when I heard his defence, I thought 'Yea, right! Hes just saying that to try and get a lesser sentence'. After seeing this video he has convinced me that he really was looking for evidence of extraterrestrials and renewable energy. He says that he saw an image of a UFO on one of the NASA machines he hacked and that it was no fake. He used a windows blank administrator password scanner, using remote desktop on a 56k modem. The only remote desktop hacking tools for windows which I'm aware of are TSGrinder and TSCrack, so he must have used one of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your unfamiliar with his case, take a look at &lt;a title=&quot;Free Gary&quot; href=&quot;http://www.freegary.org.uk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.freegary.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Project Camelot interviews Gary McKinnon&quot; href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-4252902807834262581&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-4252902807834262581&lt;/a&gt; (49mins long)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 18:17:13 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/12/project-camelot-interviews-gary-mckinnon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.dewhurstsecurity.com/2008/11/12/project-camelot-interviews-gary-mckinnon.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
